Iruka's Flying Circus
Ladies and Gentlemen!
Tonight, for your pleasure, we present to you,
a Christmas tale with a tint of drama:
"Jeremy's Tree."
Dear grandfathers, grandmothers,
papas, mamas, and, of course children!
Even those who came on their own
are welcome!
Well, well, let's get started now!
Merry Christmas!
Jeremy's Tree
Original work by Iruka
Every year, when December finally comes,
I become by all means twitchy.
Because the Christmas month
is also my birthday month.
I'm not even a Christian,
and yet, every Christmas eve, I offer a prayer
of gratitude for the happiness of being alive.
But also, I pray that we don't forget
that there are countless people and creatures,
stricken with sadness,
under this very same sky.
Wouldn't it be nicer if everyone was happy?
This story you're about to see - Jeremy's tree
is the materialization of this pious wish of mine.
Powdered snow is falling on the flowers in the field
Let's go play around together,
because it's a wonderful Christmas eve, Jeremy!
Wave your hand, Jeremy!
When you break into a run,
the morning sun glitters on your hair
All the time, I keep hearing it -
Mama's voice from the long-long past
Jeremy, hold your head high
Jeremy,
with a smile!
Wherever you go, hit it with a bouncy step
Keep going always straight ahead,
without ever looking back
However, if you see someone crying,
there's no shame doing that
Jeremy, hold your head high
Jeremy,
with a smile!
Wherever you go, hit it with a bouncy step
Wherever you go, bouncy step...
Wherever you go, walk with a bouncy step...
A wizard's Christmas cake!
Merry Christmas!
Hey, you!
What are you doing with that cake?!
Stop, you!
After I shook it up like this,
I can no longer return it...
Hey, guys! Anyone's hungry here?
Bon appetit!
Well, about time we begin the Christmas party!
What was that?
Poor thing. She's chilled to the marrow.
No need to be afraid.
Thank you very much.
Hey, tell me, where'd you come from?
I came here flying from a faraway forest...
From the forest?
Yes.
I came here to find the fir tree
that I spent my whole life with.
The fir tree?
Yes.
Deep inside the forest,
spreading out its green branches
in all directions,
it is ever so gently
watching over all of us, the fir tree.
To me, it was like a mother.
Back when I was little, I suddenly found myself
all alone in the nest.
But despite that,
I've not been feeling one bit lonely.
Felled in the forest, fir tree
The silver stars are an illusion
They don't suit you, not one bit
But they do suit me...
Standing still,
my fir tree, ah...
Tell me, do you still remember it - that forest?
Where me and you slept away those long dark nights...
Felled in the forest, fir tree
At last, I came to meet with you
I'll follow you, my beloved dear,
Even in the hereafter
Come back to life, my fir tree!
Your branches are still in the prime of youth
While the flames keep blinking...
I was hoping to return home
at least a single branch of it.
I want to live once more
together with it in the forest.
That sure is one heartbreaking story.
The fir tree that you so cherished,
chopped off like that...
Alright, I know what to do!
We'll both look for that precious fir tree of yours!
Huh? Really?
Really!
So? Is that your tree?
It's not.
And this one? Is this the tree we're looking for?
Doesn't seem to be it.
Doesn't seem to be this fir either.
That's one luxurious mansion!
I bet they've got a splendiferous
Christmas tree too!
Amazing!
It's my first time seeing a party that dazzling.
Ah! There's the fir.
This looks similar to my forest's fir...
Try calling it.
If that's the fir you're looking for,
it'll surely react!
No doubt about it!
It's the fir from my forest!
Give me a minute.
I'll go ask if we can have
at least one branch.
Good evening!
You see, there's a small bird,
who needs that fir tree you got...
Ah... Ah!
Tightwads!
Like small kids!
Maybe if I try asking once more...
After we went through all this trouble...
Ah... The lights are out!
What should we do, Jeremy?
Doing what Santa Claus does.
Except that the chimney is not an option.
Ah!
Looks like they forgot to lock it.
Good evening.
Merry Christmas.
That's our fir!
A branch!
The fir gifted you one of its twigs.
Thank you, Christmas tree!
Well, let's go now.
Rats!
Who's there?!
Jeremy!
Stay strong, Jeremy!
Strong!
Jeremy...
Jeremy!
Jeremy, you can't die here!
You silly thing.
Why would I be dying?
Jeremy, I'm sorry.
It was my fault.
It was for me that you...
It's fine.
As long as you got to meet that fir,
it's all that matters.
I wish I could go to the forest with you.
Jeremy...
Jeremy... Jeremy!
Santa Claus!
Father Santa...
You know, I have this fir twig...
I know all about that, Jeremy.
No need. No need to explain.
Now, what should I present our Jeremy with?
I want to fly away
to carry this twig back to the forest!
I see! Want to go to the forest, then?
Splendid, splendid!
I suddenly feel so drowsy...
Sleep tight, Jeremy.
Next time you open your eyes,
you'll be in the forest already!
Today is Christmas.
All the people are frolicking around,
like powdery snow.
As a result of that encounter on a city corner,
between a small bird, looking for a fir tree
and a young boy, living all by himself,
on that Christmas night, deep inside the forest,
the boy settled down for an eternal sleep.
After some winters passed,
a fir tree had sprouted from that spot,
gradually growing big and strong.
And so, a great many
of small birds have made pilgrimage to that place,
where tenderly,
tenderly, they sing it
the sweetest lullaby ever.
Friends from the Beech Forest,
Have you all gone to sleep already?
Tell me, o wise Grandfather Moss,
The sad story of love of Princess Nettle
If only you know this old legend,
will you tell it to me?
This is my favorite lullaby
before going to sleep
When I open my eyes,
it'll be a brand new day
Let's go to faraway towns,
meet the people there
Would they be happy
if we brought them a bouquet of herbs?
Maybe the thorns in their hearts would then peel away
From somewhere, I hear the ringing of sheep bells
Even the wind had already fallen asleep -
see you tomorrow
As the moonlight blankets me gently, I will sleep.
Original translation
Timing
Translation to English & TLC
Quality control
Raw provider
Аццкий Критег
World_Houp
Perevodildo
Ziusudra
WOWmd
Brought to you by the Sorcery Party
ѫ~ѫ
"Lux in Tenebris"