Let's go!
Nobody told me they have actual shells!
Shit, we need to reorganize our formation for actual weapons!
Retreat! Retreat!
You really hope to stop us with police tanks? Your anti-terrorist countermeasures are a laughing stock.
If in the next one hour our demands are not fulfilled,
This new deadly infection spreading will plunge Tokyo into terror.
Our intentions are quite serious, so I really hope there would be no misunderstanding.
Misaka dispatches!
[Misaka]
Prepare the main weapon! Draw a bead on Tokyo.
What?
The ship is under attack?
What could that be?
In the sea, they are target in the National Safety Agency jurisdiction.
You did it, assholes!
Women?
It's too late already!
If projectiles detonate, the anthrax will begin spreading through the air!
On your courtesy, all of Yokosuka will extinct! Become the capital of death!
Bullshit! You managed to defuse it in such little time?
[Field Operations Planning Center]
A call from Public Safety Research Bureau?
That's why we decided we'd better let National Defense Force handle it.
Gentlemen, the incident has been resolved.
Are you sure, Awataguchi?
The leader of terrorists is dead.
The rest of perpetrators are also eliminated.
Well, well.
Everything resolved without National Defense Forces intervention.
In the wake of this, they may promote you to National Defense head deputy, aren't they?
After the military intervention had failed so tremendously, politicians advocating it are better be much less vocal.
I don't want to be admonished by some police officer.
Well, well, the incident has been resolved safely. We don't need to confront each other anymore.
Vice-minister Awataguchi, who should we be grateful to for resolving the incident?
Secret anti-terrorist team.
All I know - their code name is Siamese Cats.
- Mission...
- Complete!
[Siamese Cats: First Mission]
Today, the sounds of pop will bring you joy in "City Navigation!"
How does it feel on the road?
Your today's navigators are Jun and Naomi!
Make it Naomi and Jun, okay?
I see nothing wrong with the current version.
Meanwhile, today's last news.
This night, in the Misaka park in Yokosuka,
the terrorist cell hijacked the Misaka memorial warship and a skirmish with police outbroke.
But thanks to the organized response of Kanagawa prefecture's police, the terrorist attack has been resolved safely / averted quietly.
We're starting to live in times where there's nothing to fear.
Yet our dear listeners should also keep a vigilant eye on possible terrorist attacks.
Well then, second by second, the times comes closer for us to part.
Too bad.
But on this station, 24 hours a day, every day, we keep you informed on the most vital info.
And now a couple of tunes that best fit this night.
A New Century song, performed by Nao, "Do Willingly."
We'll transmit the song data as well, don't forget you can always download it!
When going down to subway, usual my usual way,
or leaving out back into the light,
It feels every corner of this bustling city
is buzzing like a busy bee
Gradually, I myself grow to understand,
I actually rejoice along with it inside
Then it feels like one big refresh for this city
Is there anyone who would make me stop,
who would say I'm doing something wrong,
If I indulge myself to lots of fun,
taking a peek into every single store?
Walking in the crowd, passing various people,
bumping each other on the shoulders,
We experience something new everyday.
Now things go like clockwork,
simpler is the life, clearer is the way.
And in the city, too -
everything becomes interesting,
Everything becomes the way I want it,
just like I was hoping since long ago -
I wished, I looked, I sought,
To really live as I always dreamed of
For real,
To stay forever in the "interesting now,"
forgetful of the trouble
Then, see you next week.
Worked for you Jun and Naomi.
That sure was exhausting. I just want to sooner forget how much work it was today.
Too bad, but what starts now is the data analysis / sorting time.
Ippe!
Coming!
Why do we have to do everything, even data analysis?
We already do everything else - A to Z!
Can't Awataguchi charge one of his dimwit with it?
Want something done well - do it yourself, isn't it?
Yeah, I see.
Then, I'll do my part by listening to the voicemail.
"The old man neighbor complains about my dog being too noisy, help!"
What am I supposed to answer to this!?
It's not so bad yet!
On this end, it's "The old man neighbor speaks directly to my head, as if on a walkie-talkie."
This old man neighbor is annoying, we got it, alright?
This! You might wanna take a look at this.
What is "this?"
The National Defense Forces conduct night exercises in Odaiba.
Naturally, this is a hush-hush sneak picture.
National Defense Forces, then? Isn't it just another one [exercise]?
They're trying to hide some weird-shaped object this time.
Just a moment please...
Let me analyze it for you now...
What is this thing?
Can't tell for sure, but it looks much like some new kind of weapon.
But why is it floating in the air?
Well, it's a new weapon at army's disposal.
That's about as much as we can tell from here.
But I've never seen such a thing.
Just in case, make inquiry with Awataguchi to see if he can give us detailed explanation from National Defense Force.
Okay, I'll see to it as soon as I can.
It's a mail from Naomi, the stunning beauty.
Let me read it:
"Hi Awataguchi, how are you?
This recent anonymous tip-off caught my attention.
I have attached the image file.
It appears to be some new kind of National Defense Force weaponry.
You know anything?
If you do, let me know.
Till later!"
Project Artemis got leaked?
Imbecile!
Someone help!
I grew so tired over all this walking...
How about we stop by my place?
Incredible!
I know, right?
Of the entire model range, she has the lowest clearance.
[4:30AM at Shibaura, north exit blocked]
[4:30AM at Tatsumi junction, east exit blocked]
[4:45AM at Oi Tunnel,
next to metro line 13, the disused drainage tunnel is flooded]
The thirteenth line reports, it's like the tunnel collapsed suddenly.
It's just like the Tatsumi Junction earlier!
Someone is trying to isolate the island of Odaiba!
You there!
The maneuvers result is All Clear. Now we plan to continue the maneuvers into the next stage!
The terrorists are occupying all of city gulf area!?
Gee. Can't even catch the breath after Misaka warship in Yokosuka.
This time it's the entire gulf area?
National Defense Forces safeguarding / defensive system is a mere decoration, it seems.
I told you that many times! We should have transferred those into the police care / started funding those off the police budged!
The funding of defensive system was not even planned / taken into consideration!
Vice-minister Awataguchi, is there any news regarding those terrorists' background?
Yes. Your attention to here, please.
Kaido Shunsuke!
It's as you say. Kaido Shunsuke, also known as the Onslaught of Asia.
The Self-Defense Forces veteran.
For his radical views, was discharged from army in 2000.
In 2001, during the ethnic wars / uprisings in Africa, he made a name for himself, known to the world.
Was pulling the strings for various Arab countries in oil cake conflicts.
Commanded many guerilla attacks against one of the governments.
Some say he was personally in charge behind the assassination of the president.
Wrong. The guerillas were fighting both belligerent governments that time.
He made a fortune of billions protecting the interests of wealthy states.
I see.
I also have an opinion on that precedent / matter, but we'll have to settle it some other time.
According to my information,
Kaido should currently still be involved in ethnic wars someplace far away.
Who'd think he will target Japan this time...
So why exactly a professional terrorist like him would go and seize an entire bay through military action?
A transmission from Kaido has just arrived through government channel.
I'm redirecting it to here.
Japanese government, how does it feel to finally get awoken?
I take it you are well acquainted with who I, Kaido Shunsuke, am.
I will proceed immediately to our demands.
As has been demonstrated, we are perfectly capable of carrying out operations on a global scale.
To fund my future undertakings, I would require you to prepare $800 billion in cash.
$800 billion?
The entire national budget, isn't it?
It's not such a big deal: Prime Minister Nozaki and the population of Odaiba - if you think of it as a price for all of their lives,
It's actually rather cheap.
The countdown for you to respond starts right now. I'll let you have 24 hours to do it.
If your answer comes late, even by a margin of minute,
Prime Minister Nozaki, as well as the populace of Odaiba - 35 000 people lose their lives.
This concludes our current appeal.
Also, be prepared that in 24 hours I will open this communication channel once again.
By that time, I want you to make a sound / earnest judgment / decision.
Wait, Kaido!
What are you doing? Connect to the line again, quickly!
I'm trying my best. But we're being blocked on the opposite end.
He expects us to accept all the demands unilaterally, without any negotiations.
This all may very well take a global scale, so our decision has to be total.
Try to reconnect to the line as soon as you can.
All right, then I'm sending an emergency deployment mayday signal to the National Defense Forces.
The right to deploy the National Defense Forces is exclusive to prime minister.
Then contact Prime Minister Nozaki at once / in person!
That Prime Minister Nozaki is in the hands of terrorists right now!
Alright, then call this cowardly man Hamazaki, he'll assume the role of prime minister!
Before answering to Kaido's demand, can you give me 12 hours to act?
I'm thinking of sending in the same team that repelled the terrorist attack on Misaka in Yokosuka.
The ones with Siamese Cats as their codename?
We don't know a thing about this disgraceful bunch to entrust them with such an errand of a paramount importance.
For a case just like this, our National Defense Forces have a top secret anti-terrorist team of their own.
Major Isurugi, please come in!
Isurugi has arrived.
Let me introduce...
National Defense Forces anti-terrorist department commander, also known by the name of Mighty Dog.
Major Isurugi.
Major Isurugi, how long would it take for Mighty Dog to resolve the incident?
The plan of a special tactical operation has already been prepared.
It would take about ten hours for us to have the situation firmly under control.
How about it, Awataguchi?
Isurugi can show you how to resolve this situation two hours faster than your Siamese Cats.
Time is a factor of the utmost importance now.
In that case, we'll let Mighty Dog deal with the incident.
Is that fine with you, Awataguchi?
You can have it any way you want.
But wouldn't it be wise to still introduce Siamese Cats to the case just for insurance?
Is that an order?
I think allowing multiple similar organizations into the actual battlefield would only bring about confusion.
Well, well, Isurugi.
Awataguchi's Cabinet Intelligence and Research Office also has a competent team.
Understand?
Duly noted.
It's the data from Mr. Awataguchi.
Our well-merited holiday goes down the drain.
Well, at least I have this  American souvenir from Awataguchi. Glock 26 gauge.
I really fancy this. Nice to meet you, my newest partner.
The Gulf Area is occupied by international terrorists under the command of Kaido Shunsuke.
We need to get rid of the terrorists in the shortest term.
Among hostages are Prime Minister Nozaki and the entire population of the Gulf Area.
Therefore, this time we are working along with the National Defense Forces anti-terrorist detachment.
Mighty Dog was also deployed for tactical operation.
The National Defense Forces call the shots here, so please take is seriously as well and don't turn it into a helter-skelter.
I repeat: with all due seriousness.
This data will automatically self-destruct now.
Even with automatic self-destruction. As if it was something important.
Central Headquarters of the National Defense Forces
Captain Isurugi!
For this tactical operation, like in many previous cases, we use those P90s.
Mighty Dog is ordered to gather in the briefing room in full.
Roger!
Captain Isurugi, who is this Siamese Cats organization we're conducting this operation along with?
I beg your pardon.
Huh? Isn't this where the National Defense Forces Ichigaya garrison of Mighty Dog's briefing room supposed to be?
Place and time don't seem wrong I think.
You guys happen to be the Siamese Cats?
- Here's Jun!
- And Naomi.
The two of us comprise the Siamese Cats!
Hey, hey, hey, don't overdo it.
We were told it's a first-class anti-terrorist team, not just two women!
My, you hate women?
National Defense Forces terrorist extermination detachment, Mighty Dog with major Isurugi as a head.
Nice to meet.
How about we have a dinner once the tactical operation is over?
I'm sorry, but I don't want personal feeling to affect my work.
No fun allowed, huh? / You're not cute at all, aren't you?
Let me explain the course of operation.
According to the current army intelligence,
The enemy forces are 2 submarines, 30 boats, 10 combat helicopters, and finally, leg infantry - about 100 men.
From their swift actions, it is apparent there's a well thought-through plan of attack that has been in work for some time.
Police station, as well as the new parliament building
and Prime Minister's official residence are already in full control of enemy's infantry.
Ariake Nuclear Power Plant is occupied as well.
It should be taken into consideration that in the worst case scenario, there's a chance nuclear reactor runs out of control.
Therefore I expect you to act with extreme caution.
If Ariake nuclear reactor is out of control, what are the consequences?
The entire Kanto region may end up in the giant exclusion zone.
In addition, some information that was previously classified as an A-tier military secret:
in one of the warehouses in wharf area, a National Defense Forces top-secret new weapons R&D facility is located.
Development code "Artemis."
The first in the world attacking weapon that makes a practical use of protective / defensive shield.
It's a top secret even from the army. There only supposed to be a handful of people knowing about it.
The harder you try to keep it a toppest secret, the more this info is apt to leaking.
"Is Kaido aware of Artemis' existence," is the real question now, doncha think?
Artemis falling into terrorists' hands is what has to be prevented at any cost.
Even if it means sacrificing Prime Minister Nozaki's life in the process.
Gee. Nozaki sure is unfortunate fella.
This is the decision of Cabinet Crisis Management Center.
Wait a second, you don't think sacrificing / exchanging all of gulf population' lives is also fine for the sake of this, don't you?
We have designated our approach as "from underwater."
This is the point of disembarkation.
From there, our infiltration would be unexpected,
allowing us to quickly recapture the research center and push out the enemy,
thus ensuring Artemis' safety.
On your part...
...Make away with the bozos occupying the power plant.
In other words, our job is to minimize the possibility of Gulf Area population being exposed to danger.
A standard anti-terrorist objective in the wartime.
First, we shut the enemy's ears and eyes.
If you manage to seize the power plant, you will be able to stop the electricity supply.
That would wreak havoc in enemy lines.
One way or another, all is fair in love and war.
Captain!
I have an objection to this plan.
Are you sure it's safe to entrust the nuclear power plant to a bunch like this?
How about instead of dispersing our combat power...
First, a small warning:
Don't judge about them by their appearances.
They have access to some serious information source of their own.
Top-secret as it is, the existence of Artemis was no mystery whatsoever to them.
Then, remember the playfulness with which they sneakily invaded the very heart of this garrison.
Besides, in the recent Misaka warship incident, they were the duo that resolved it.
Then, we can now proceed to the main stage of operation.
Equipment is a special wristband.
The operation plan was downloaded in everyone's personal memory.
Roger!
Good luck in the fight.
Same to you.
It's not very nice to ask, but you're looking exactly where I'm looking, aren't you?
Maybe.
But I wonder, will he really expose the entire population to danger?
He won't have to, / It'll be all right, if we resolve the incident before that happens, right?
Perhaps.
[Telecom center]
Do you guys have a single idea about what you are doing?
We have not yet once caved / We would never cave in to terrorists' demands!
Had we been average terrorists, I think I'd do so myself.
But this time, whether the government decides to save you and the entire gulf area populace
by paying up the ransom or not paying - does not matter in the slightest to me / actually I'm fine with both.
What are you talking about?
You don't have to pretend. I will now dispel all your doubts at once. Come in!
Professor Kaneko!
Prime Minister! How come you're in such a place?
Wait. By bringing professor Kaneko here, don't you mean to say...
Don't tell me your true goal is...
Forsooth. Development code "Artemis."
The new generation weapon on the spearhead of Japan's military development capacities.
But it's supposed to still be far from completion!
It's no use to feign a denying expression now.
Isn't it so, Professor Kaneko?
Rest assured, Prime Minister. It's still far from completion.
Too bad for you. You came through so much trouble to come here just to have your hands on a pile of scrap iron.
Next, professor, you'll tell me you didn't report to highest army ranks about their top secret project successful completion?
Very well then.
Saito, report your progress on Artemis.
Roger.
As the speak, a scrupulous examination of Artemis is being conducted in the assembly hangar.
With much effort, we deduced that part of the algorithm that connects each section is missing something / is flawed somehow.
What is missing?
The factor that's supposed to hold the key seems to have been artificially removed / seems to have a man-made omission.
Is that why you claim it to be incomplete?
What are those key holding factors then?
About that... Unfortunately, it'll take a lot of time to introduce you to the basics.
I understand.
Try to hasten up the analysis on your end.
On this end, we'll also be collecting the info independently.
Roger that.
In the meantime, try to politely untie professor's lips.
About what this key factor thing is.
Got it? Subject him to some insistent / serious politeness.
Roger that.
Torture me all you want, I won't spill a thing!
Letting Artemis fall into your terrorist hands.
The world... The world will diverge into darkness / will be destroyed!
"The world will diverge into darkness." That would make for a good catchphrase / slogan.
Don't you think so too, Prime Minister Nozaki?
The world has already been to darkness before / is already a ruined place.
Since it gives birth to devils / gave birth to a devil of your abominable kind!
That's good too. Splendidly said.
Ariake Nuclear Power Plant
Well, I leave the rest to you, Ippe.
I got you. I'll be waiting for orders while maintaining the status quo.
Meow~~
Hi!
Jun, mission...
Get to start!
This way.
Close call.
Two mice sneaked in.
We ain't no mice, mind you.
Listen carefully now. We're the team for erasing the filth / the most hideous bastards from this world...
Siamese Cats!
How pretentious!
Stop! If we destroy control systems here, it'll be beyond salvageable.
Quite right.
While it doesn't concern me in the slightest if some control system here breaks or whatnot.
Main system is destroyed. Switching to subsystem.
Now, what do you do?
Wanna go on fighting like that?
Or maybe you act with prudence and don't sacrifice not just the gulf, but the entire capital populace of Tokyo?
It's time for an entertaining interrogation!
The guy that hides behind your backs...
If you don't crack willingly, you'll end up just like the grandpa over there.
Now...
Crack!
Tell me!
It's no fun at all this way. Just one more thing then...
Before continuing it with you, why don't I finish off the grandpa?
Stop that, you.
Perfect. That kind of bloodthirsty domination / assertion is my favorite.
Stop it!
Yes.
Yes. Roger that.
Lucky you. We'll have to postpone the fun until later.
Until I come back, behave and be quiet.
Professor! Are you okay, Professor Kaneko?
Who you guys are?
Vice-minister Awataguchi from Cabinet Intelligence and Research Office sent us to help.
Awataguchi then...
I see, you two must be the Siamese Cats.
Yes. Let's cut and run promptly.
Listen! I managed to slow Kaido down.
His main target was Artemis all along.
The calamity guys don't know what a key factor is, which is necessary for the start-up.
But they'll figure it out eventually.
Key factor?
That's right. An ingenious system to prevent Kaido and the likes of him from using it for ill purposes.
It was designed to only be possibly activated by a person carrying a specific genetic information / code.
What do you mean?
So... who is this person, carrying a specific gene?
It's my grandson Kazuhiko.
Please, protect Kazuhiko from these villains.
We've got you.
You did a great job, Siamese Kittens.
Now that we heard this explanation, you are no longer of use.
Rest in peace. / You'll be disposed of.
Hurry! They are running away!
Hang on, professor!
Are you okay, Professor Kaneko?
Not at this rate...
I can see them! This way!
They're running away!
You can drop me here. Forget about me and flee!
My grandson... Help my grandson Kazuhiko.
Shit!
You're late!
I'm sorry, there has been a confusion in the upper ranks.
Instead of securing Artemis, the order was suddenly changed to extracting Professor Kaneko.
Then, we'll entrust Professor Kaneko to you.
We have some other place to go now.
Professor Kaneko, we will keep our promise.
Until then, take care of yourself.
Where are you going?
Geez.
Cats sure be self-willed.
Professor, let's get you out of here.
No, I can't go yet. We have to get to my laboratory first.
At any cost, I must activate Artemis's self destruction.
I wasn't given an order for that.
Screw the orders! Fate of the whole world is on the line now!
I got you.
Ippe, do you copy?
Operation plan changed, surface urgently!
Here we go.
Ippe, get us to Tokorozawa, will you?
Tokorozawa?
Am I a taxi driver to you?
Not quite, but very close.
Either way, hit the gas! / hurry up!
Gotcha.
The enemy is moving underwater! (Muzzu's variant) / I got them underwater on the radar! (my less likely option)
Don't let them get away! Follow the trace at once!
Roger!
Just as I thought, we are already marked. Well, we can also be speedy / springy.
They sure won't let us go that easily.
Look at the road!
Kay, kay.
Shoot-shoot-shoot!
Hey, it's only the shore there!
Well, look at this.
What... Follow them by water!
Not bad, right? Well, I can do even more than that.
What a bright boy!
I don't know a thing about this Awataguchi from Cabinet Intelligence and Research Office.
Why in the world did they took us off from an actual terrorist attack site?
What were they thinking! / I know, right? Our mission here is just babysitting some kiddo!
Where is this helicopter going?
No idea.
Closing in on the target point.
Anti-terrorist units of police are here to protect the target.
What a stupid-looking bunch!
Fire!
Shit, look at what it did to us. And we still don't know anything.
Alright, the storm troopers can now recover / secure the key factor.
Nonsense... You weren't supposed to reach Tokorozawa as quick as we did!
Making the impossible possible is our job.
That's Siamese Cats for you.
She'd done for.
Let's hurry up to make sure.
What just... The hell was that?
I wonder...
A poor fella.
There's another one. Chances of surviving such a crash are nigh zero.
What?
Bullshit...
Are you a terminator by any chance?
Stop right there. And drop the whip.
Hit her!
Idiot, it was me!
Now you'll stop. / That's where you'll stop.
Wait! You won't hit her now!
Jun!
Jun...
Wait for me, Jun!
Two more left...
Last...
It's moving us somewhere!
Sluice?
Auto-tracking: Lock on!
Here!
Grab it!
Faster!
What just... / How could she...
Cabinet Intelligence and Research Office, huh?
I've never seen a license like that.
Anyway, I'd like to thank you guys for your service.
When you have a chance, report to Vice-minister Awataguchi from Cabinet Intelligence and Research Office about us, will you?
As per his orders, Siamese Cats have taken Kazuhiko under their custody.
- Bye.
I don't know a thing about the Cabinet Intelligence and Research Office. What's with this attitude?
What a cocky guys! Right?
Pretty.
Hey, sis.
My grandpa... He's all right, isn't he?
Your grandpa is perfectly fine. After all, it were we who saved him.
But that means grandpa was in danger?
Maybe a bit. But it's all right now. He was lucky to have us, Siamese Cats by his side.
Grandpa...
You love your grandpa, don't you?
It's all good now. No need to worry.
Everyone, buckle up! / get a hold of something! It's getting a bit bumpy now!
Steer in the woods!
Roger!
[National Defense Forces R&D Facilities]
Enemy is near! Regroup!
Scatter!
Captain! We'll give you a respite now to activate the Artemis self-destruction system!
Professor Kaneko, why did you start it up?
The self-destruction system also draws energy from nuclear power reactor.
In order to do that, starting up the machine first is unavoidable.
There's 10 minutes more on the countdown.
Understood. Buy us 10 more minutes.
I'll think of something.
I count on you.
In just a bit more, I'll protect Artemis from those devils.
Thank you, Professor Kaneko.
Not only you told us where to look for key factor, you were also so kind as to guide us through the start-up procedure.
Kazuhiko will also soon arrive here.
At this rate, you'll get used to touching reunions.
Stop it! Don't you dare to lay a finger on Kazuhiko!
You can leave him there. He won't be able to pull anything more.
Out to the open already?
Where else should I go? This forest is not remarkably or and wide!
Sister.
Here.
What is it?
Sister, is there a chance you'll see grandpa first, before me?
Yes, perhaps, that will happen.
Then, I want you to give this to grandpa.
He said that in times of danger, I should grab this and keep it close.
But... Right now, I believe grandpa needs this thing much more than I do.
You're a remarkably caring kid, Kazuhiko.
I got you. Sis will make sure to pass this to your grandpa.
Can we seal the promise?
You have my promise.
Asshole!
No good! I can't shake him off!
Shit! It never goes as planned!
Ippe, faster!
Shit!
Kazuhiko, can you hear me?
Your grandfather is in our hands.
Grandpa!
Don't do it, Kazuhiko!
Get out at once.
Otherwise you won't be able to see your grandfather.
Moreover, you'll get blown up together with that good-for-nothing / foolish bunch.
Kazuhiko!
Wait! Don't do it!
If I go with you, will this rescue grandpa?
Quite right.
What about those sisters?
Certainly.
Kazuhiko, you shouldn't go!
Kazuhiko!!
Damn it... Couldn't even protect one child's life.
Key factor successfully secured.
Well done, head straight for laboratory.
Roger.
Key factor has arrived.
We could have been fellow scientists by now!
Don't you know a hint of shame?
Kazuhiko!
Grandpa!
I implore you! He doesn't know anything!
Don't hit grandpa!
Only if you can enter this thing for us.
Artemis...
Connecting chamber extended.
Connecting chamber opened. Key factor boards!
Connecting chamber insertion completed.
Initial connection commenced.
With key factor in, Artemis' algorithm is finally complete.
Will the machine finally come in motion? / Will we finally see the machine in action?
All external power is off. Unplug crucial connections.
Roger.
Your Grace, preparations are all OK.
Artemis, start up!
First lock released!
Takeoff / Start-up order confirmed.
Main bridge disconnected for start-up.
Second lock released.
First supporting leg removed. Analogically, second supporting leg removed.
Axillary power supply cut off.
Internal power supply cord: connected without abnormalities.
Artemis: take-off preparations completed.
Stop it! Artemis should never be guided by a hand of a devil / should never fall into devil's hands!
Professor Kaneko, by your grace, finally, Artemis will become mine.
Don't you understand how with your intentions a road to world destruction is paved? / how you're guiding the world straight to ruins?
Thank you for this valuable advice / for cheering for me, professor Kaneko.
Artemis: take-off!
Hey Artemis, as a tryout / for a small check, obliterate Hamamatsu city.
Splendid! Destructive power is beyond expectations!
The world is destroyed...
This is Delta 1! Closing in on the target!
The target is confirmed dead ahead!
Moving in to attack!
A shield!
Regroup for evasion maneuver!
Is there a nation that can withstand that destructive power? / No country has ever faced that much of destructive power.
With just 10 Artemis more...
No, even five will be enough.
A world hegemony would no longer be a dream!
Temporary withdrawal!
Major Isurugi...
The time in which he promised to take terrorists under control has well passed.
It's over! The state of Japan is no more! / It's the end of Japanese sovereignty!
Awataguchi! What became of your vaunted Siamese Cats?!
There's still one hour left until the Siamese Cats' planned time of tactical operation conclusion.
One hour?!
In one hour, Artemis will already turn Tokyo into a sea of fire!
This is Isurugi of Mighty Dog.
Major Isurugi, current whereabouts?
I am inexcusably sorry. At the moment, I'm following after Artemis.
Please tell me, what is Artemis' weak spot?
Weak spot you say?
She'd never become a weapon if she had any!
Isurugi, this is Awataguchi from Cabinet Intelligence and Research Office.
Artemis' weak spot is the defensive shield generating head!
Awataguchi! This is a state secret disclosure!
This state's survival is jeopardized now.
It's not the time for maintaining secrecy!
Thank you, Vice Minister Awataguchi.
What a pain! Where should I hit it to make it collapse? That colossal meat grinder.
How is it going, Ippe?
Connection completed.
OK...
Will this thing really be enough?
I made it on the go by improvising.
Not giving any guarantees.
It consumes all the energy of the entire nuclear power plant. A Beam Bazooka.
But the energy consumption is truly enormous. You can only make 2 shots.
Just two shots?
We'll have to do with just that.
Wait a minute!
Still impenetrable?
I don't like this! It'll obliterate us before we do it!
Here I go!
It's now!
Hit it!
Hang on!
You...
Ippe, the thing is useless!
What did I told you! Of course it can't penetrate the shield!
Artemis has...
It's alright.
Artemis' weak spot is the head.
Shield generating apparatus.
Understood.
Once we complete this mission safely, why don't we have a dinner?
So you know a thing or two about having fun after all? / So you can be a little cute, don't you?
Ippe, take care of Major Isurugi.
On my way!
Later.
Jun!
Artemis' weak spot is her head!
When I turn off the shield, hit there!
Got it!
Kazuhiko...
Yes! She managed to sneak inside the shield!
Jun, don't rush. It's far from over yet, Jun.
No need to go that crazy / do anything stupid, Jun!
A smidgen of rest before going for a last push.
I can get really scary when pissed off!
She did it!
It was close, too close. / Mine sure is a dangerous trade.
She friggin did it, Naomi! Shield is called off now!
Once Jun escapes, I'll go for it.
Gotcha!
Self / Auto-regeneration function?
Naomi! The new shield will be deployed in a moment!
Shoot the second one right now!
What are you talking about?
Hurry up and escape from there!
It's terrible now, shield generator is recovering at a fearful rate!
Quickly! Shoot right at me, Naomi!
Jun!
Hurry!
Shoot...
I'm doing it, Jun.
Jun!!
Naomi, where are you going?
Naomi?
Evacuation!
Your Grace Kaido, please hurry!
Whenever I saw the opportunity, I brought these mercenaries along to seize it promptly.
But now they're all just running away like some mice from a sinking ship.
However, Kaido, this is not the end yet.
Saito, you brought along the Artemis data?
Yes, I have the disassembled and rearranged data on Artemis' algorithm stored in here.
Watch out!
Kaido.
There is no forgiving such a dick.
Naomi, right?
Been a long time since Africa.
I certainly didn't expect us to reunite in Japan.
This time, are we enemies or allies?
I surrender.
If that means being shot by you, I'd love it.
Did you forget the rule of a warrior's goodwill?  / Haven't you forget the ultimate goal of a warrior?
Asshole. Even now, you're still just as craven a guy.
Craven?
To a terrorist, that's rather a compliment.
Rest in peace! / Farewell!
Jun!
As always, you're falling victim to empathy.
You, Naomi.
But how? Jun, how did you make it out alive?
Remember when Kazuhiko gave me this locket?
Turned out to be a mini shield grenade / one time generator.
Jun!
Kazuhiko?
Kazuhiko...
It was thanks to it that we all got saved.
I'm so glad!
Gentlemen, the incident has just been resolved.
Prime minister is safe.
Prime Minister Nozaki?
With all this Artemis turmoil, I completely forgot!
The death of Kaido Shunsuke, the attackers' leader, is confirmed.
The rest of them deserted or something of the kind.
Brilliant as always, Awataguchi. This time again, we owe it to you.
Yeah, I always knew it's the Siamese Cats who can really get things done!
My patience / trust with them paid off! / My decision was not a folly!
Hi! Everyone among listeners! Today we have a special issue of "City Navigation."
We're broadcasting from the gulf area, occupied until just recently.
The gulf area, as well as the neighborhood has suffered a significant damage from the terrorist attack.
But through the hard struggle of police and National Defense Forces, it was taken under control.
Congratulations, congratulations.
According to police, the remains of terrorists
have been promptly cornered and arrested.
So what did we did at the end of the day?
Just provided a succor for those girls?
These two are pretty.
The police also seems to be quite content to have this incident resolved.
And now, we present a new song right away.
Nao's second hit, KEΦI.
After this song, we'll continue our live feed so stay tuned / so don't alter your tuning.
Mission...
Complete.