Toki Shouzou's Private Detective Trouble Notes
Hard and Loose
Harder! Like this, like this, like THIS!
I am coming! Coming!
'Right, getting there.
Sorry for this.
Crap. I wrecked it...
Hello, Mister Toki?
Is something wrong?
No, I am all fine.
This is the Telecom Service, a client phoned your office. Connecting you right now.
Yes, please do.
Hey, how were you expecting a call in my house?
Shush!
Yes, Toki's detective agency here.
Detective agency?
No, have no worries.
A 24 hour help time limit still is our motto. From now...
Never mind, it's no problem at all.
From now?
Aoyama's Elf coffee shop.
Got you, I'll meet you there in 30 minutes.
Luckily the first job in a long time, can I really afford to leave him hanging?
Hey, what was all that about?
Are you a private detective?
Never introduce a man in your bed before you know his name and profession.
But I never heard yours!
Since you had been so playful, I wasn't going to address the subject.
If you are to be my friend, you should have known better.
What are you saying?!
We've been together for two weeks!
I wish I could stay longer, but duty calls me.
Get out of my sight!!
Women and their tantrums...
Must be a really serious deal,
As even that call forwarding broad had an agitated tone in her voice.
Mister Toki?
The client?
You surely are a shrewd one,
We never agreed on a code to recognize each other.
The venue sufficed!
More importantly, what is he up to?
That client gave me such a first impression.
It may seem bizarre, but I'd much appreciate if you took it up.
Surely an odd one.
You want me to befriend that man to better spy on him.
Here are all of this man's places,
Make it as if you were dating a woman in the first place.
However, you already have that guy's whereabouts,
Why not a direct approach?
I need it to look as a coincidence, so I need a pro and a stranger for that.
I see.
It's settled, let's do it.
Much obliged, here is your advance.
By the way, I was wondering, why picking me out of all the detectives?
Actually, you are the fifth choice.
Oh, I see.
On the spot, the previous detectives didn't quite cut it.
Can you channel geekiness and enthusiasm?
Geekiness? Enthusiasm?
Hardly. Still, you want me to play the goof?
So this guy, Tashiro Seiji, turns out to be a real estate agent.
Shinshu Soba
Welcome!
Here you go.
Thanks for the meal!
It's like watching a silent movie, only it's a buck instead.
So far, I have his profile.
How can that tight-lipped guy be an actual real estate agent?
This makes it harder for a stranger like me to make friends with him.
I can't think of a single way in to make a good impression, he's that type of guy.
At this rate, I have no other choice than refund the 150,000 advance.
Hey, small fry. This nasty stain is gonna cost me, ya know.
Asshole! Quit acting unconcerned!
Whassat, whassat, eh?
The bastard spilled beer over me and now act carefree.
What? Is 'dat so?!
What? Unfazed?
Impressive, After a few scattered blows, still landing a one-hook K.O.
I haven't met a man that tough in a while.
Cash that out as a payback for the stain.
Time to make an exit.
How many beers did you have?
Two bottles. And two tipples.
You paid this low end pub way too much!
That one was a good punch.
As good as your save.
I just couldn't stay idle.
Aren't you now short of one place to hang out at?
No worry, I'm used to it, by the next week I'll be someplace else.
Good, how about we resume the drinking at my fav' joint?
This time, it's on me.
I'm Toki, Toki Shouzou.
Private detective.
I'm Tashiro.
Thus, the client's assignment has been fulfilled, without I even faking friendship.
Well, during my student days, I was in boxing gym for some time.
That's about it.
I knew it.
In fact, I myself was once part
of a local gym's boxing team.
We had one hell of a good time back then, during the golden age for boxing...
Fuji Takeshi, Gushiken Yoko,
Pressure Onishi!
Pressure Onishi...
Truly fine times.
Yeah, He's the fighter I most look up to.
That being said, I recently stopped going to Korakuen Hall.
Same for me.
Then, paying the entry fee was the promise of a good fight.
Yeah, boxers these days have side occupations, fighting merely as a hobby.
A gospel truth.
The ring calls whom has nowhere else to go, it's either getting good or bust.
In short, if there was a machine to weight the soul resolve,
It'd be the end all of any pro test!
Huh?
Yo, Housemousie.
What gives?
Are you about to be drafted to war?
Huh?
How pitiful that that woman makes you frog jump back and forth.
Do you ever question if that's how it's supposed to be?
Mister, are you some sort of psychologist?
Dufus,
My job's private detective.
And your income?
Depends, different every month.
Well, no matter what, I won't be like you.
Go for it! I count on you!!
Once again, the guy's lights are completely out.
Hurrah! You did it!
Tonight, we're celebrating!
A fine ending of a month!
Look, just enjoy life, you'll meet even cuter babes.
Let's go party!
No, I prefer this place better.
You sure like stiff drinks.
Gaudy places aren't my thing.
Then, let's just hit the red lights district!
Please, nothing about women...
Are you... One of those?
Nonsense!
I just feel that way right now, that's it.
Gotcha.
Is it a cold woman that looked down on you?
Well, let's stick with that.
A sociopath?
He won't drop a word extra,
That Tashiro guy reverted back to being impenetrable.
As though he was hurt badly once.
Detective Toki listening.
Hello? Hello!
It takes a lot of effort to call a detective but less to expound your case to him.
You're a lucky one, as I am a detective keeping it true with his motto.
Now, as frustrating as your trouble is, my rate is fixed.
Have no worries on that.
My situation is special...
Huh hmm,
I see.
Okay, let me handle it.
State your name first.
Mister Onishi...
Onishi Shugoro...?
Unless, don't tell me...
Pressure?
Mister Pressure Onishi??
I was... No.
I am a huge fan of yours!
Your reversed techniques, like the rear uppercut!...
Yes. Got it!
See you at your designated place, looking forward to speaking to you then!
Thank you.
Pressure Onishi, to talk to him was a honor.
However big of a fan I am, he's still over a hour late!
Damn.
How... How did you tell?
How could I forget the boxer's face I so admired?
This, is more than 15 years old,
I've lost shamefully since then!
As a punch-drunk bum.
As a fighter!
It confused me when you told on the phone that you are a fan.
This doesn't justify running away.
Fair enough, so can we talk business now?
Without a doubt, unless you dodge me.
It's about Kuniko and not losing favors with she,
I can't swallow it.
I have been cheated on!!
Why does she prefer a young salaryman over me!?
I think I understand. A rival in love.
I want you to investigate about it.
Assignment accepted.
I will kill that man.
Don't do that, I can't be mixed up in these stories!
I beg you, play along!
I'm in high demand lately,
Guess I'll keep either going.
Hello?
This is Toki calling, I need Mister Kubo.
Oh, Mister Toki?
Ohh, have you been doing well?
Yeah. About time for the next step.
Wait just a moment,
Checking the schedule.
By 9:30 pm on the 18th bring him to the Figaro restaurant in Roppongi, okay?
9:30, got it.
You will notify me about that person, understood.
At this rate, socializing with my friend Tashiro will fall upon me.
It's Tashiro.
Hey, Toki.
Much obliged for last night.
Never mind it.
Are you available this Thursday evening?
Yeah, every once in a while, I hang out in trendy places.
I don't mind at all,
But instead, how about tonight?
It's the payday, so I can repay for yesterday.
Hmm, working?
Yeah, tonight got work to do.
Then, come along as a friend, yeah?
Listen, I'm going to that bar because of the job offer, keep a low profile.
Understood.
So, what are we looking for?
Can't tell yet.
There's a gag order involved after all.
Fair enough.
But please, let me treat you tonight.
Gonbei Tavern
Here, this is the place.
Refill.
First time here, gentlemen?
Kinda. On the way from work.
So, you aren't in this district for fun?
In the summer, isn't this place crowded with youth in the afternoon?
Occasionally, yes.
I see.
However, rowdy visitors are quick to kill the good mood.
Dealing with youth can get tiresome, a matter of age probably.
She's a good woman.
Such a smooth skin texture, despite her mature age.
- Madam, the bill please.
- Yes...
She is fine,
Don't you think so?
Is she?
Still, you seem to not appreciate womanhood,
An everlasting aftermath?
I can't say so.
Bar friends are still bound to have some dating experience.
I do have one, of course.
That man sure experienced a break-up!
Heh, you've seen a lot of these, Madam?
You were betrayed by a woman, weren't you?
Is that the reason of your mistrust?
Nothing of the kind happened.
Still, you can't recover from it.
I don't know what's on, but I'm fine with what I pieced together.
Please keep it that way.
No problem.
Although it's not habitual in my trade, I will.
Are you a weekly magazine reporter?
Ah, no...
In due times, I'll tell you everything.
Gonbei Tavern
Madam, please give us the bill.
Huh? On it.
Gimme a second.
Sorry for the trouble.
Have a nice evening.
Hey, I recognize that guy.
It's... It's...
It's him!!
Darling, don't thrash the place!
Calm down, Mister Onishi!
Toki, watch out!
Toki!
Darling!..
Toki! Toki!
Hang on!
You two better run away now, Mister Sunglasses might regain consciousness anytime.
Right! Our bill...
Never mind that, just go!
We're sorry.
Well then...
Are you alright, Toki?
Y-Yeah.
Made it out in one piece.
Still, how uncanny,
What was his deal?
That man was the reason for coming.
That man?
Unbelievable.
Infidelity frenzies men and women.
It really does.
I'm no less surprised than you are.
Don't you have an idea of who is that?
By his punch and stance, certainly not an amateur.
He's a former pro, the name's Onishi.
Onishi? Pressure Onishi?
Exactly.
No way!
If it was him, he'd never let me land a punch like that!
I'm lucky to get off that easy, the bastard was well soused.
This fist connected Pressure Onishi's face, surely a lifetime memory.
Ditto.
Not everyone can brag being KO'd by Pressure Onishi.
Yes. Toki's detective agency.
Toki, is that you?
Are you fine speaking right now?
No, actually, I found something of interest.
What is it?
A real estate advert.
That bar is for sale.
Yeah, although the other company manages it, this place ringed a bell. It indeed is Gonbei.
But the hostess never told about putting it in the market.
Surely, it has to do with that guy.
Meaning, Pressure Onishi took a heavy toll on the place.
Thank you, I'll be on it.
We'll get in touch later.
Currently, I dread that Pressure Onishi is going to commit a homicide.
After all, I'm his loyal fan.
Either way, this man's prime years are long gone.
So, That's the person of interest.
Hello?
It's Futaba Real Estate's Satou.
This property... Yes.
Gonbei's tavern.
I think it meets your price very well.
Yes. Are you in the city now?
This is going to be really cheap deal.
Yes...
I'm sorry for last night!
Are you hurt?
No, I'm alright.
It doesn't hurt anymore.
I'm the one to be sorry.
Actually, this is my occupation.
So, you're a private detective...
As a matter of fact, Mister Onishi hired me.
With what bidding?
More importantly, is Mister Onishi often like that?
He goes on rampages every three days or so.
Huh?
The doctor said he developed a punch-drunk syndrome, from being punched too often.
Punch-drunk syndrome?
Initially, that was the main issue, but it has been getting worse ever since.
He is now raving about I having a paramour.
Huh, so, about that young man...
Can it be that he asked you to investigate it?
Ye-Yeah.
Found anything?
No. Nothing.
Can I ask you about one more thing?
Why is this place on sale with such a low tag?
It's getting too tiresome...
It's between me and that man, all the deal's money will go to him as part of an agreement.
I can't see any other way, but go someplace far away.
Starting all over again.
You know what I mean?
In just a week the deal will be over with!
Please get him to see sense!
I figured it out, your hatred is groundless as the woman's innocent.
Damn idiot!
You've been fooled by her as well!
Calm down, Mister Onishi.
You all treat me like a punch-drunk bum!
That's not what we think.
You... You say so as that punch took you out cold easy!
You better disappear, get it?!
Well, until she flees, those will not be the final words I get from that former Middleweight boxer.
I've been watching Pressure's back ever since.
That same guy we encountered at Roppongi?
Yeah, none other.
Let's mind about women other than his.
Which of them?
Who can be that person?
Our manager, Mister Kubo, will be an hour late, it seems.
Isn't that Shijo Eiko from 'Japan's got talent'? In Roppongi...
Tashiro...
Eiko...
Oh well.
For some reason, I could tell how a woman had a part in it.
Mister Toki!
It's been a long, long time.
Well, what a great success it was!
You could have spared me the shock, if you told that the third party was TV celeb Eiko Shijo.
What's on between those two?
I thought confidentiality to be part of a detective's policy.
It is, of course.
Here is the rest of the money, for the grand finish.
'Been a pleasure.
If you excuse me, then...
Not the conclusion I expected, but a deal is a deal.
That leaves only Pressure to put a check to.
A boxer with a shattered dream...
Bewitching woman and her shape ups
A week has passed since Tashiro's last call,
But I'll stand by just in case.
Yo, Housemousie,
Full of energy, as ever!
Mister, I am spent.
Whatcha say, isn't she a fine woman?
I'm sure you know.
'Just an article.
You can take a good look.
There's nothing wrong with you, just don't change job from now on.
No, I'm completely fine with that one.
How so?
Well, no matter what, I won't be like you.
See you around.
Ah, Mister Toki!
I was waiting for you!!
Uncle, what happened?
It's no good. I couldn't reach you by phone,
That affair with Shijo Eiko and Tashiro didn't go as planned!
Huh?
By the making of this TV drama, Shijo Eiko had an important contract signed with a sponsor!
What contract?
A one-time extension, stating that she must lose an additional 5 kilograms.
5 kilos?
For actresses on american television, it's a common practice, still...
As her manager, for her debuts, I tried to get she to regain her early beauty!
Yet, she didn't fall for it!
You were going for a ploy to motivate her?
Yes, precisely.
Hence the matchmaking with a lover from then.
That's what you wanted Tashiro for...
Seemed like a viable idea in paper,
Sex and romance, getting those 5 kilograms to vanish in a puff of smoke!
And the result is evident.
That's what I meant, it's all there!
Shijo Eiko's new lover becoming obvious,
When the reporters started to spy on them, they run away!
Huh hmm.
Please!
If the girl stays on the lam, we're screwed!
Name your tag, but take this case!
Okay, I'll get back to you if there's anything...
Please do, I am off to get more help! Excuse me!
I'm going to Hokkaido,
Whatever happens in the future,
I'm starting a new life with Eiko.
Tashiro.
It is out of my hands.
Onishi looks a bit different from yesterday.
He might suffer from another fit.
Th- The hell are you doing?!
Hey! Return my truck!
As obsessed with the woman as he is, he unconsciously does it!
I still remember of our last meet's right uppercut with fear.
Don't do it, Pressure Onishi!
That uppercut you dealt me showed how much of a boxer you still are!
Is that what maddens you?
Don't act as you understand!!
Having a chance to fight you made me happy!
It was a lie, wasn't it?
...Being happy that we fought.
As bad as it sounds, it was true.
Even then, I owe an apology.
No, You have nothing to excuse yourself for.
Can I ask you about one last thing?
Yeah?
Are you still deeply moved by my fighting style?
Yeah, it sends chills down my spine still, that's boxing to me.
As for me, I crave to see bouts as thrilling once again...
I am sure many feel the same.
I see.
So, that's how it is...
Night, fists,
And finally, the man's dream.
Everything dispersed along with the fog.
My assignment ended there.
Brought to you by the Sorcery Party
ѫ~ѫ
"Lux in Tenebris"
Translator: Perevodildo
Timing/Check: Ziusudra