Aim for the ace
!
OVA-2 (1989-1990)
—
Final Stage
Under the skies that are still unknown to me
I know, you're doing just the same -
Dreaming
Just a small glow
From those great days
Is what dragging you along
Giving you faith and some comfort
Under the sun that scorches badly
I only want to see your guise
But instead...
I only watch
With tears on my face
As you slowly disappear in this noon haze
We're alone
Walking this world on our own
Looking for each other since long ago
In the end, in the end,
After the day we finally meet
We won't ever have to say "Goodbye"
Thank you, Oka...
I'm even more convinced now, I love you.
Episode 2
My 19th Summer
The sea, you say?
That'd be great...
But you know, I have to attend the club every day.
My "menu" is very strict...
What? And that's gonna stop you?
Coach Katsura is at the shrine again, right?
No one else can stop you from going!
Practices can wait for a while, but house by the sea can't!
There will be eight guys and three other girls!
Don't you see we have a shortage without you?
Can you imagine how eager everyone is
about meeting you?
Too bad, but I really can't be absent for three days.
I might get a call while I'm there.
Who are you getting a call from?
You just said, "I might get a call while I'm there."
Whom from?
Amateur champion Takayuki leaves the country
It's too late to deny now!
Did I really say that?
Not gonna tell?
I'm intrigued...
So, who is he?
I don't believe you meant coach Katsura!
Todo...
Tell me... what is happening to you?
Where have you gone, and why?
TV only gave me the idea of your plans.
Your intention to become a pro...
Your intention to drop out of university...
I tried so hard, but I couldn't reach you by phone...
I believe you now have
more important matters on your mind.
I understand that completely.
But just a single call... would have been enough
to relieve my soul from something that oppresses it...
Cause since that rainy morning...
Since that morning...
we didn't say a word to each other.
You're Ms. Oka Hiromi, am I right?
Sorry if that seems inconvenient to you.
I am a "Sports Toto" journalist, and I hope you won't mind
a quick interview if we give you a ride home.
Todo will be the subject.
Ms. Oka, you both graduated from Nishi High, right?
We are writing a short biography of your friend Todo.
We have already talked to a few of his close friends.
Yeah, but when I came to him today
for a personal interview, he politely refused.
Came to him? Todo didn't tell anyone his whereabouts.
Have you found him?
Not gonna lie, he's good at hiding,
but we are even better at seeking.
Won't you please share
the location of Todo with me?
Sure! But take it easy,
we're the ones supposed to interview people here!
I'm home!
Welcome back.
Mr. Todo, actually...
moved to Kamakura,
to one of the Buddhist shrines.
Yeah, though I never heard he was religious.
Hiromi? Are you leaving again?
Yes... I'm...
I'm going to coach Katsura's shrine.
His training instructions are unclear to me,
so I wanted to...
You will pay him a visit that late?
Won't you at least have dinner with us?
Yes...
But have you warned him?
You sure you won't disturb him that late?
It's also starting to rain.
How about you come back now and go there tomorrow?
The racket should be shrieking while cutting the air.
With great power comes control.
Isn't it time to take a break?
It isn't!
As long as you keep complaining,
don't even dare to dream about improving your style.
If your training is indulgent,
you are no national championship winner!
I'm sorry, my dear, if it will destroy your hopes, but all men
are the same, and only a few among them are unique!
I'm sure the main thing
is not to give up and keep looking!
Alright! We all wish Ms. Wei from Yamashita good luck!
And now a letter from Shimano, from Ms. Keiko! Let's read.
"I'm convinced the love is dead..."
Already interesting!
"My sister is a traitor, and I was so blind!
I don't want to see my sister! I only want to die..."
But...
Todo actually...
As far as I know, in two weeks he is leaving for America
to continue his training there.
In just two weeks?
Right...
But before that,
he wanted something else done. Here in Japan.
Many thanks!
There's nothing to fear, Hiromi...
What are you doing here?
Take courage!
What happened to the training plan I left you?
It's just... Actually...
Why did you come here? You should be at "Park Hill" now,
performing power training upon my instructions!
And that's exactly why I'm here! I can't take it anymore!
This lonesome practice drives me crazy, therefore...
Coach, I beg you to let me continue training here!
What...
I swear, I'll be engaged every day
and won't cause any inconvenience!
Greetings, Todo...
Oka... Greetings.
Oka...
Yes?
I won't banish you out of here,
but you're gonna have to work hard.
Also... be prepared that I'll have no spare time for you.
Are you serious?
I assume you took your two weeks' belongings with you.
Yes...
You can stay in the room
where you used to live before.
Okay!
You have a talent! Chiba, I had no idea
you are that skilled in playing the piano!
I was in middle school
when parents first made me take lessons...
The piano was your first passion,
but then you switched to the camera?
Well... yeah...
Todo and I...
Have met not long ago.
Of course, I let him know about your demand for a meet.
He expressed no objections, you can visit him anytime...
But be aware that he is now preoccupied
with pro-test preparations.
With coach Katsura?
You know already?
Yes... One of our mutual acquaintances
informed me where to find him.
Since you are going to meet Todo...
Do you mind if Ozaki and I will accompany you?
Sure, if you wish to.
But what for?
To avert injustice towards him.
Injustice? I was just going to have a talk with Todo.
I doubt this meet will have anything in need of averting.
Madame Butterfly, you have objections
against him becoming a pro.
You're wrong...
No. You have received a lot of sponsorship offers,
but you aren't trying to become a pro.
That is a matter of my personal judgment.
Answer me then,
what will you say to him?
Won't you be questioning his decisions,
his personal judgment?
You have some very wrong ideas about me, Chiba.
You and Ozaki are not the only ones
to call him a time-proven friend of yours.
During our education at Nishi High,
we played countless matches in doubles.
What's the matter, Todo?
Do you think that making just two thousand swings
might be enough to call it a day and ease up?
You still lack confidence in your hands,
and your timings are in need of a lot of polish!
The power should guide your racket
since you're an overripe player already!
Right...
An overripe player?
Todo is already overripe?
He said that Todo in his early twenties
is an overripe already... How is it possible?
That's just nonsense!
Good morning.
Morning...
I'm glad to see you're doing fine...
Right...
Since our last meeting,
I have called your phone countless times.
TV made me worry about you...
when they said you're becoming a pro and going abroad.
But... since our last rainy encounter back then,
for some reason you seemed so hurt and lonely...
How happy I was...
to find out I wasn't the reason for this.
Your becoming a pro isn't the consequence for my rude words,
but your own well-thought decision. And still...
I'm terribly worried about it all. I have no idea what to do.
Of course, I still love you no matter what... But for now...
If things go that way,
and we'll have to part again...
I can't imagine what should I think, what should I do...
Even the idea of breaking the bond with you brings pain.
I'll be fine no matter what, Todo. There's just some inexplicable anxiety about your journey, in my chest...
Will you be fine too?
Thank you...
Well... Coach, I brought this with me.
Please treat yourself.
Todo, you too.
Have some.
Thank you.
This is called "Sports Drink." With orange, pine, peach...
Oka!
Yes?
What's with one thousand serves and strength exercises!?
Why aren't you on the roadwork now?
I've already finished it!
I got up early today.
Then...
You can rest now.
Go to your room and save energy for later.
OK!
Sports drink, want some?
"Oh, my dear Maki...
I hope you're spending your days as great as I do.
I'll never forget this nineteenth summer of my life, have my word!
Cause the summer spent
in such a beautiful place one certainly can’t forget!
Here I have a wholesome climate, wholesome food,
and wholesome company! What else is needed?
Still, even that is not the main reason,
why I'll remember this nineteenth summer.
Something even more special happened here...
I think, in ten years or so,
I could tell you the whole story...
That's all for now.
Wholeheartedly yours, H.O."
What made you begin avoiding our company, Todo?
And what's the reason behind your silent demeanor?
We have created so many bright memories together...
In the courts of our high school and the tournaments.
Please let us know the truth, Todo...
How come that after finishing the climb, one doesn't stop
to catch their breath? Why do they continue to climb ahead?
What makes you think that "the climb is finished"?
Who said such nonsense?
If Todo... becomes a real player,
it will not be the end, but rather the beginning!
You have no idea at all
for what is waiting for you...
Cause in the pro world, no matter how hard you try,
you only reap suffering.
Still, you deliberately doom yourself to this.
What for?
- Madame Butterfly!
- Chiba...
Please don't keep us in ignorance, Todo.
What delusion forces you to climb further without us?
I'm begging you to explain it!
Coach Katsura, you should understand
what I'm talking about better than anyone.
Why aren't you trying to convey to Todo
the idea of how wrong he is?
We both understand that Todo is an overripe already.
Why aren't you stopping him from going to the pro world?
I have no right to stop him.
Todo chose this path himself.
Madame Butterfly, I don't get it at all!
Todo is just twenty-one years old!
Just like me, Todo started playing tennis
at the age of eight.
From the age of eight,
we both started spending all day long on the court.
Does it make the idea clearer for you now?
In middle school, we regularly won prizes.
For six high school years, one should rise
all the way up to his regions' top of the players.
Does it make the idea clearer for you now?
The speed of reflexes, the strength of the serve,
the strength of the body...
In boxing, athletes are retiring when they are this old,
and tennis is no less severe sport.
Please wake up and see that you are
about ten years late to the world's top!
Especially if you start climbing at twenty-odd years!
The time when thirty-year players
could make it there is long gone!
Tennis is so extreme that its future champions
are being trained from infancy!
So they come to their peak prepared.
But you are already past it...
Hey, but what if Todo could just...
Todo... You and I really had a chance to become pros
if we started to strive for it back in middle school, but not now!
When the peak of our strength was about to come!
Not at present when everything is behind us!
Right now, in the pro world, our experience and technique
wouldn't stand a single compare to a common player's!
Our best efforts will have no effect at all!
Don't you still get it, Todo?
Why are you trying to do it despite everything?
Why do you still choose this foredoomed path?
For the same reason...
coach Munakata then...
started to teach tennis the newbie Oka
and not the experienced me, which drove me mad at first.
She was the first-year then!
But only recently I realized I was already on my peak
at that time, and had nowhere to rise...
That used to frenzy me before...
I was certain that I will never forgive coach Munakata,
even if he would try to make amends for it.
Todo... I love tennis no less than you do. Tennis is
my whole life, but I don’t dare to dream about becoming a pro.
As an amateur, you can always play tennis at your own pace,
even for your whole life, if you wish to. Just like I will...
I am worried about your future,
with all my heart. Like a true friend.
Thank you, Madame Butterfly. Thank you... There's not a single thesis
in your statement that I could argue with. Thank you...
I wanted to keep it a secret.
But it seems there's no point
concealing even personal issues from old friends.
I should have
talked to you earlier.
When Munakata Jin fell ill and quit sports,
he was about twenty-one years old.
That is... pretty much my age now.
Therefore...
had Mr. Munakata eluded his incurable disease,
I wonder if he would continue his professional career?
What is your opinion? That is my only question.
He would have become world-famous,
working and sweating without a hint of fatigue.
But fate had other plans... He fell sick and then left us...
One genius player Munakata Jin, who raised us all.
So as his student, I feel the need
to continue what he began but couldn't finish...
I feel that I have to do this
as the one wielding a still healthy body.
I was initially prepared to face the fact
I might be too weak to reach the end either...
At the age of twenty-one, he was forced to back off
from this path, but I will continue it!
Everything Madame Butterfly said is right.
The peak of my strength is already in the past.
Mr. Munakata played his first tennis match when
he entered high school. But I play since I was only eight.
It might be very well the truth
that in terms of tennis I'm already an elder.
However...
However, I thought it through.
I believe in the choice that Mr. Munakata did
because he saw the way here!
And this faith he put into my heart too,
so I cannot give it up!
I'll try again. If I have reached my peak already,
I can definitely get there once more!
My decision to quit university...
The decision to become a pro...
Won't lie, I hesitated a lot.
But in the end, I chose to go forward.
When if not today?
One should not put off until later what he can do now.
For I don’t want Munakata Jin to become just an intangible
memory for us! He shouldn't be forgotten like that...
While what he started is still alive...
I believe... While we keep moving, he is alive!
What happened, Oka?
I thought you were staying for two weeks straight.
Excuse me.
I'd better go home...
That place is so crowded because of me,
it might interrupt your hard work.
But tell me, Todo will clearly pass his pro-test, right?
Well, who knows...
Whatever is ahead,
please don't give up.
There is one song I cannot ever forget
Still, there's a face I'm willing to forget
With her feelings messed up,
Alice got completely lost
The midst of summer
Brought her into one tricky love maze
I want you to hug tightly
And never let go of me,
One scared and timid tiny girl
I quite remember our very first kiss
And the beginning of all of this
While birds were singing for us...
I'll take a car and take a lonely trip
I know it'll bring me
To the seashore
Where only the the sun,
Dazzlingly bright,
Could witness my long-awaited happiness
Aikawa Make here.
The day when Todo embarkes on his long journey is here.
But we should not be sad about this.
We should keep our chins up!
Right, Hiromi?
Can you imagine, on the day of departure, coach Katsura organizes
a training match with Madame Butterfly. What a heartless coach!
Hiromi, hang on!
You might run out of time to say goodbye to him!
Coming soon: "Never Say Goodbye."