Aim for the ace!
OVA-2 (1989-1990)
—
Final Stage
Under the skies that are still unknown to me
I know, you're doing just the same -
Dreaming
Just a small glow
From those great days
Is what dragging you along
Giving you faith and some comfort
Under the sun that scorches badly
I only want to see your guise
But instead...
I only watch
With tears on my face
As you slowly disappear in this noon haze
We're alone
Walking this world on our own
Looking for each other since long ago
In the end, in the end,
After the day we finally meet
We won't ever have to say "Goodbye"
Amazing...
What a dashing game, dear viewers!
Another set point is being played already!
Ryuzaki is aiming to finish the match quickly!
We've got a champion!
Player Ryuzaki wins the championship!
Ms. Ryuzaki, is there anyone,
who you want to dedicate your victory to?
I dedicate it to Ms. Oka.
My present shape wouldn't have been possible
without Oka's effort.
And why her, exactly?
In this tournament, of all the girls,
she was the most challenging opponent for me.
Episode 1
I'm even more convinced, I love you      !
Everyone of us has a dream.
That's just how human nature works.
Our kind needs something to dream of.
And if we don't, the life turns into an endless stream of remorse.
I have a lot of dreams myself,
and I'm not giving up on it.
Believing in your dream isn't enough.
You gotta pursue it, decisively and selflessly.
And may I have no peace until I make sure
that I have made every effort to fulfill my dream.
- Easy to say, Chiba...
- And you are no exception!
While your dream is still alive,
you have to aspire to it! By any cost, Todo.
Oka should come here today too, am I right?
Yes. At 2 p.m. she is free from her studies.
At 3 p.m. we have training.
Let me introduce, coach Katsura.
These people are from a respected
local advertising agency.
Since Oka is under your custody now,
it was you her coach who they wanted to meet.
I hope I can help you.
Well... You know...
Mr. Katsura's trainee Oka
turned out to be a hidden gem,
whose unexpected tournament triumph
astonished the world of women tennis.
Her matches at the Japan Championship
demonstrated everyone,
that even being unknown to anyone,
you can still show great courage and achieve a lot.
We are convinced, she'll be a perfect image
of how our company does its job.
You should understand this more than anyone -
if you're aiming to continue her growth,
sooner or later, you'll start working with us.
Will Oka... become a successful pro
under your patronage?
Exactly. A lot of newbie players raised by us
are national heroes now.
And after this tournament
Oka will undoubtedly become a pro too.
Alright, Oka. Enough for today.
But usually, we do a hundred more...
Enough I said.
You'll spare more time to rest instead.
I am very grateful!
Let me clarify one thing right away.
Your work should not interfere with our training.
The player is distracted because of you!
Coach, who were these people filming us?
Our practice seemed so interesting to them...
Do not mind them.
Just a few old acquaintances.
Munakata Mansion
I'm back.
Welcome back, Daigo.
You want some rice?
Yes, I'm completely exhausted.
Thank you.
It was a very...
important day for us, Munakata.
I noticed that lately,
we mention your name less often than before.
Don't get me wrong,
but I'm happy with it.
That means... Oka, Todo, and Ochou
are already on the path of overcoming your death.
No more grief. No more sorrow.
Their hearts are open again for whatever is coming.
It was you and you only who taught them to walk,
but flying they'll have to learn themselves.
And you are starting to turn into just a memory.
But what a bright one...
Hiromi... Are you sure?
Won't you catch a cold?
It'll be alright if you prepare a hot bath for me. Okay?
Still, maybe you skip it just once?
Impossible. I have to run every morning to keep fit. I'm off!
Good morning...
Oka... Good morning.
Under such heavy rain... a roadwork.
What happened to you?
What's wrong?
Everything!
Take it.
You'll catch a cold!
Hurry up and dry yourself!
You scared me back there...
It was the first time I saw you that devastated...
Sorry... I was thinking about the training,
forgot about everything else.
I'm the one who should apologize...
Todo, you are... the most clear-headed person I know...
Clear-headed! And wholesome!
You are equally bright, strong and good at tennis!
And also handso—
That's why... I was so shocked.
Thank you, Oka.
Now I'm even more convinced... I love you.
Ryuzaki Mansion
Reika, isn't it time for you to come out?
Yes... I was just about to go.
Look here, please!
Here.
According to our news sources,
a lot of Japanese sports equipment manufacturers...
Or, at least, the three largest companies on the market
have offered their sponsorship for your future career.
Ryuzaki Reika - Successful Amateur Tennis Player
Are you ready to announce,
which one you will work with?
As a professional,
have you made up your mind upon a plan for your career?
Are you disappointed in becoming a pro? Do you regret
the stop of your victory streak in amateur league?
Unfortunately, for now
there's nothing I can tell for sure.
I don't feel sorry about giving up on my win streak,
however, for now, I have nothing to tell about my plans yet.
My pro-career completely depends on the will
of my father, who is much more experienced in that matter.
"My pro-career completely depends
on the will of my experienced father..."
That statement sure was amusing, Reika...
However, have you really not decided yet,
exactly how your life will go on?
I was sure that you did.
And that you just chose not to share it.
Father, since you understand this yourself,
please rid me of these questions.
I am more concerned about Todo...
He is planning to leave his university's tennis club.
And as far as I know,
he's leaving the university as well.
What is the reason?
I wish I knew... His resignation letter just caught my eye
while I was taking some documents.
In the casket, which only I have a key from,
my memories will find eternal rest.
The hardest thing for us is finding someone intimate
for the depths of our hearts.
Thus, I can't help make your journey justified.
Tell me... How much more of this babble am I gonna hear?
Just show me where you hid the money!
For eight years...
I humbly suffered humiliation and ridicules.
All this time I was more of a servant for you than a wife,
and still, I didn't say a word!
You can't imagine how many dreams
I had to put in a box and ribbon it...
Aikawa!
Maki!
And after all this suffering,
I haven't ever heard a single word of love from you!
The Drama Club presents a play:
"One Step to Midnight"
Starring: Maki Aikawa
Gotcha!
You were so natural, Maki!
The last episode genuinely scared me!
Maki, jokes aside!
You looked like you were born in this role!
Playing tennis didn't do the trick for me,
so I decided to be good at playing roles.
It will come in handy one day.
But "Park" is so prestigious! I really wouldn't want
to drop out of there, even though I don't play myself!
Knock-knock!
However, is this indeed what thou be dreaming of?
Whichever the path thou choose,
thou have a future full of opportunities!
So, what did you want to talk about?
You invited me here because something bugs you, right?
There's nothing I want to talk about.
It has just been a long time since we were out together.
Glad to hear. For some reason,
you looked all lost to me, Hiromi.
I assume your practices are even more Aika-wild now,
aren't they?
More than ever!
Hiromi, do you know what you'll do as a pro?
Your tennis career!
Have you forgotten you have one now?
I didn't...
Don't tell me... You haven't thought of it even once?
Keep in mind... I became a pro, like,
five minutes ago.
That's a fact...
At least, you are already a real player,
and I'm still so far from being a real actress...
And now, the last subject — tennis news.
Winner of the Japan Inter-University
amateur Championship, held last June,
Todo Takayuki — Champion of University League
Todo Takayuki announced
his transition to the pro league.
The young champion also revealed
his intention of leaving Japan
to meet the world's finest pro-players
and come back as an experienced player.
And now, the weather forecast...
Ozaki is listening.
Yes, it's me.
What a surprising call! Long time no see.
I am always happy to hear from you.
Yes, it's mutual. I haven't seen you in "Park Hill" lately,
so I started to worry.
To be honest, the last few weeks I had no time for tennis.
No, I'm practicing when I can. Fifty-fifty.
The thing is... This Medical Faculty exhausts me completely.
Yeah, after all this studying no energy for tennis is left.
But I understand -
that's not the actual reason behind your call...
As far as I know, he wished to be left alone for a while.
And that recently he stopped answering his phone.
What happened?
I want you to tell me the whole story.
People say he's going to some kind of journey...
I heard, in two weeks he'll leave Japan for a while.
What's wrong, Oka?
Quit making junior mistakes!
I'm sorry!
Oka...
Yes?
For the next two weeks,
you will be practicing without me.
I prepared a practice menu for those two weeks.
We have mastered ball handling.
Next is developing your physical strength.
And don't slack just because you're alone.
Excuse me...
When I'm back in two weeks,
you better be through this schedule. See you.
Coach!
Excuse me...
But why are you leaving so suddenly, coach?
I'm just your coach, I don't have a duty to report to you.
Therefore, see you in two weeks.
Can you at least tell me, where are you going?
I'm heading home.
The shrine is going to deteriorate if it's not well cared for.
Thank you, Oka.
Now I'm even more convinced... I love you.
Successful student Todo Takayuki becomes a pro.
The young champion is about to leave Japan.
Yes, Oka family is listening.
Mom, has anyone been asking for me?
Asking for you?
No, there was nothing like that.
Are you sure? Maybe on the phone?
Why do you ask?
Are you expecting someone's call?
No, just checking to be sure...
Nevermind. Thanks for the answer.
Todo Takayuki
Isamu Ozaki
Takashi Chiba
If you won't come to me,
I will come to thee.
It's Todo. I can't answer the phone at the moment.
I am terribly sorry.
The traffic is a little crazy these days.
Ozaki invited me to come here.
If I recall right, you managed to contact Todo and spoke to him.
Chiba, please, don't keep us waiting.
That indeed happened.
But in the current situation, there's nothing we can do for him.
His unusual behaviour is caused by his personal issues.
If so, can you at least tell us, where he is now?
It'll be unfair for you not to share his condition with us.
I'm afraid... I have no right for that either.
But I can assure you there's no reason to worry.
Whether he is now running, or just crawling,
he made his very first step upon the road he chose.
"I don’t want to see anyone for now..."
That's what he told me last time.
Why?
His path may be thorny, but he's obliged to walk it vigorously.
And we must not interrupt his journey.
The Nishi High Tennis Club
has changed so much after meeting coach Munakata...
Everyone is going their own way now...
Not minding the others at all.
Makes sense... Ever since my graduation from Nishi High,
I was feeling some kind of loneliness on the court.
That's not true, Madame Butterfly!
And I'm sure Hiromi feels our connection breaking too.
Madame Butterfly...
Two weeks is not enough to achieve anything of matter,
but we'll still be doing our best. Come!
Every single minute is precious here.
Don't waste 'em!
I'm at your service!
To become a pro in tennis,
it is not enough to just pass the test.
Have doubts about what you're doing -
forget about becoming a pro.
Live every day like it's the last one - become a pro.
Wanna play with the best players the world can offer -
first prove everyone you are a real pro!
Todo... Your path will be unbelievably difficult.
I understand this.
We are bringing your tennis up to the world level!
When you start hating this, don't complain!
I understand this!
I still...
I still believe I can do this!
Alright, Todo! In two weeks you'll be a professional.
And you will pass your pro test!
Yes!
I noticed that you train all alone for the last few days.
Are you doing fine, though?
Yes... I strive for the best no matter what.
But to be honest,
such a practice feels a little off.
You can always call me out.
I look forward to practicing with you.
Are you serious? I'm so grateful!
Then...
Excuse me...
Excuse me... Maybe it's just a rumor...
Ms. Ryuzaki, since you're on good terms with pro-world,
maybe you know if what they say about Todo is true?
Had that been a misconception,
you'd be the first one to know, Hiromi.
Coach Munakata raised us all.
If it wasn't for him, we wouldn't have tennis and all of this.
That's what he said.
There is one song I cannot ever forget
Still, there's a face I'm willing to forget
With her feelings messed up,
Alice got completely lost
The midst of summer
Brought her into one tricky love maze
I want you to hug tightly
And never let go of me,
One scared and timid tiny girl
I quite remember our very first kiss
And the beginning of all of this
While birds were singing for us...
I'll take a car and take a lonely trip
I know it'll bring me
To the seashore
Where only the the sun,
Dazzlingly bright,
Could witness my long-awaited happiness
I'm Aikawa Maki.
We're now on our way to the seaside training camp!
We're gonna make the most of
our 19th summer!
But for Hiromi this summer will be difficult.
Todo suddenly takes the undreamed path.
I feel sorry for Hiromi.
Actually, to do this, Todo even asked Coach Katsura for a special training.
But, coach, why do you keep saying that Todo is not young enough now?
Coming soon: "My 19th summer."