Bank of Japan Note
Ten Thousand Yen
With Pictures
An Introduction to Japanese Economy
Suddenly we met
While just passing by
Meguriai surechigau
Thanks to cars going around back and forth
With their headlights on
kono machi o ikikau Headlight
Chances are your dream
Anata no yume
Gave you a cold shower
tsumetaku kawashita
When remembering those times today,
ano toki no watashi o
I don't feel like myself
kuyande shimau
Ah once upon a time
Not a single of those faces was around
Ah once upon a time hito wa dare mo min'na
But you were so hurt,
You didn't want to see them anyway
kizutsuku tame ni deau wake janai no
Thank you for your love
Every time we meet somewhere,
We have to part again
Dokoka de aeru to wakaretakedo
Not a single of your friends
Tomodachi ni mo
Not even your beloved one
koibito ni mo
Will ever wish to return to those times.
You know it, don't you, love?
modorenai koto dake wakatte ita
Japan-US trade frictions
Welcome Ms. Matsumoto Sawako
Is she really coming by that plane?
Maybe I got the wrong flight number...
Or she simply passed by.
"Taihei Shoji" sent you to greet me?
I'm Matsumoto Sawako.
Taihei really is acquiring a brilliant employee!
I don't get to greet a Harvard graduate every day!
To go studying abroad one needs a lot of wits and guts.
Seeing you here with me is almost like an illusion!
Not only that,
you got a master's with summa cum laude!
The fact that you could get the first hand American idea of automobiles is just unbelievable!
I can't express, how much I admire you!
This traffic jam is strange...
It's not even rush hour yet.
This happens every time I find a passenger!
I see... Well, we still have a little time.
Ms. Yukie, why don't we take a walk?
Let us get off here.
October 1980
USA, Detroit, Michigan
How many cars do you think
America has produced this year?
Last year, due to a sudden surge in demand,
it was a million and 480 thousand.
Japan then became the world's number one car manufacturer. The United States remain number two to this day.
We are boycotting the Japs!
We don't need their scrap!
If our union is idle, we will act ourselves!
We've had enough of chinks!
Give us back our job!
It's a Japanese one!
We'll make them pay!
Let's get the Jap's car destroyed!
Eat this!
Burn to the ground!
Central Automobile Association Chairman, Hoffman
It's me. I want to make a call to Washington.
Hoffman must be one hell of a happy about that.
Showa Automobile Company President
Under such a great pressure,
Washington might demand actions from us as well.
Showa Automobile Company CEO
In turn, the Japanese government won't hesitate
to comply with their American colleagues.
And of course, our government
will accept all of the restrictions,
because it's the only way to protect themselves from all the political and legal blame.
Those parasites have no idea that once Japanese cars stop getting to the market, our economy will collapse.
This will only lead to the increase of price.
And this is, indeed, exactly what they are aiming for.
If the price rises, the number of Japanese cars sold will fall.
In fact, "Central" will be the only one to benefit from the trade turnover decrease.
I'd like to believe those frictions are temporary.
Some people make fortunes playing money games like this one. They'd do anything for profit except improving their means of production.
While we reduced the number of workers
to one person per vehicle,
even applying all the rationalization means they know,
they can't assemble a car with less than three persons involved.
But I'm afraid,
this industrial action is bigger than the previous ones.
Are they planning to ban imports
to increase their own cars' sales?
Indeed. Workers' protests are just a public excuse.
And they won't leave the streets until their wish is granted.
But don't they understand that a market rivalry is wholesome for product's cost and quality?
It already forced our Hayate colleagues to relocate their assembly lines this year.
Although it didn't affect us so far...
Still, we should foresee this shift
and face it prepared, is that what you're trying to say?
We'll have to do it, sooner or later.
To save our money, actions have to be taken right away.
Main Business Headquarters
Export self-restrictions have been placed.
The government didn't even try to resist.
I guess we won't see a planned 1 680 000 cars next year...
Well, such turn of events is to be expected.
Anyway, I'll hand it over
to the president and see what he says.
Why, you...
President! The telex just came, just as you said...
Self-restrictions placement? No need. Hayate
automobile company president just called me to discuss it.
Oh, I see...
Ms. Matsumoto, Hayate's are grateful for your advise to move production lines in advance.
No... It's not a big deal,
anyone could do the same thing.
We appreciate your modesty, but thanks to your forethought, Hayate are fully prepared for the following crisis.
Your advice to move production lines has played a big role.
We cannot ignore such foresight.
Or, at the very least, when the Showa Company needs it,
we should give this 23-year-old talent a chance.
Well, it's just a girl
who graduated from Harvard Business School.
You don't need a lot of talent
to just go studying abroad!
Manager, just because she's a woman,
you mistreat her?
Ms. Yukie...
In fact, I mentioned it
because Showa carmaker recently contacted us.
Showa you say?
Your work for Hayate impressed them. They want to hear a lecture about production relocation from you.
So Showa are also seriously considering relocating their production lines back here?
I can't say if they're serious yet. Mikawa and Matsumoto, wouldn't you mind to meet their president on this Saturday's evening?
Unfortunately, I have to refuse.
On Saturday I'm leaving for a private consultation in Kyoto.
Why, you... This company is virtually a market monopolist. Will you give up the chance to work with "Showa"!?
All the details of the Hayate's production relocation process are recorded here.
This notebook will be more than enough
to solve any problem they might encounter.
Kyoto
I was anticipating these events long ago.
Residence of Sawako's benefactor, Kyoto University of Economics and Sociology professor, Funaoka Muneichiro
Once the restrictions are placed, the price of Japanese cars will rise to an average of $2,000.
Without export, the overproduction
will supply the entire prefecture with cars.
No, we'll even have some left for change.
In its turn, the American cars price rise
will deplete buyers pockets.
As a result,
ordinary Americans will be the only victims, isn't it?
Glad you figured it out yourself.
It's all leading us to forming a Japan-US monopoly cartel.
However, I think we still have time before that happens.
What makes you think so?
The currency market...
American foreign trade after 1970 became financially scarce.
Surplus      Scarce
Japan-USA Foreign Trade Profitability Charts
Blue chart - Japan
Billions of dollars
Red chart - USA
Since then, every year the scarce has been increasing, falling deeper into the abyss...
Year
(Note) The proportions of the axes are not respected
(Source) Nomura Research Institute, May 1984 data
You can only imagine how irreparable
internal budget hole has become.
And to somehow fill it, the government plunged into a bunch of external public debts.
But as you well know
neither external nor public debts have been of any help.
Yes.
Thus, now to pay off all of America's external debts,
the dollar, which has become the world's currency, has to be printed in the unthinkable amount.
It will be an infinite stream of dollars.
Needless to say, how the dollar's exchange rate will drop then.
Its price will fluctuate like the sea during a storm.
The yen will rise when dollar gets cheaper?
Exactly. Each dollar, which now worth more than 200 yen, will then cost 170 yen, if not less.
And chances are the worst is yet to come.
But if things go that way, won't maintenance of production lines in America will become even more profitable for Japan?
You got it right away.
And then we'll only have one problem left...
...Local working conditions deterioration?
If that happens,
our subcontractors will suffer the greatest damage.
If you are looking for Showa subcontractors,
this should fulfill your interest.
You are...
Archive manager, Yuki.
Apologies... You weren't on the spot,
so I helped myself.
I work in Main Business Headquarters...
Ms. Matsumoto Sawako, isn't it?
Right...
This lively girl has already introduced you.
Ms. Yukie...
I always come here for dinner, you know.
My...
In the late seventies, I was amongst the many who got exposed to the unpleasant experience of selling color TVs and other junk.
And I know firsthand
what a big deal car production relocation is.
Right...
By the way, if that would help, I can get you color TV production relocation recordings.
That would make a great help!
Well, where was it...
Say, Ms. Yukie, this Mr. Yuki, the librarian.
What kind of person he is?
Main candidate for the head of the department and big careerist. But sometimes he looks like something is bothering him...
Like he is coping with responsibility for something from the past. I often see him standing by the window, deep in thought.
With Pictures
An Introduction to Japanese Economy
Two years after the first export self-restrictions
Japanese cars became more expensive.
The American auto industry increased the prices as well.
Central Association has just started handling with this crisis.
However, America has suffered financial reforms,
which strengthened the yen further.
Meeting of the Central Automobile Association shareholders
The price for Japanese cars
is about to rise once more.
I am happy to announce that we defeated injustice without resorting to the price increase.
Unfair working hours, government disloyalty to workers, and other ineffective Japanese means of competition
have been officially denounced internationally.
Japan was obliged to radically change its foreign policy course.
But most of all, I am proud that the dollar-yen exchange rate has remained at a reasonable level.
The Japanese cars' competitiveness reduced drastically,
and as a manufacturer I hope too,
that soon enough our companies will start relocating their production lines to Japan themselves.
If we call ourselves Americans,
we have no right to lose in that industry.
So I, as the Central Automobile Association president,
promise you to start exporting our cars to Japan in a matter of the next few years!
We've had enough of their jokes!
As long as they accept all the petty American demands, we only become poorer!
Showa Automobile Company Workers Union Chairman,
Katsutoshi Sato
It's you and I, ordinary workers,
who suffer from this more than any of them!
For the sake of preserving our union,
we must confront them!
Give 'em hell!
Have no doubt that we are the main victims of those trade difficulties! That's right, comrades!
At a working meeting this morning it was decided that we are not moving production lines away from America, in spite of expenses.
Therefore, we ask you,
Goyo and Taihei representatives,
Goyo Manufacturing and Business Committee
President Gondo                         Kunio Tsugawa
to discuss during this meeting,
how our local factories will work from now on.
I want you to come to a compromise solution.
I get it you are being easily swayed, since you now even employ girls fresh from school.
Mr. Tsugawa, please watch your mouth.
Okay...
Mr. Toda, don't you think you really are being too soft?
No, I'd say it's you who are being too soft.
Can I ask just one question regarding the matter?
Please, go ahead.
Labor unions,
have you already figured how to deal with them?
That issue should be out of your concern,
we have our own ways to negotiate with them.
This scoundrel Gondo regularly gets swayed by shady specialists himself.
This time I was even close to punching his nose...
President, please let me figure this out.
After the Hayate issue, I came up with this secret strategy of production expansion, which they won't be able to reject.
Oh, I hope this is something worthy.
I had an idea
that we might just inherit local factories on site.
I'll write a report due to this evening
so you'll see it yourself.
Sounds good. Ms. Matsumoto,
do you happen to have any alternatives?
I'm convinced that research among subcontractors
has to be conducted.
Subcontractors?
What is it out there that I can't tell you right away?
If you have nothing else to do besides that,
you'd better come and help me with my idea!
Sorry for returning your own words,
but the Goyo Committee, most likely,
has already taken the first steps towards new potential sites.
But if we show the ability to look from a different angle now,
in the long term, Showa will prefer to appeal to us.
Besides, this has to be done at any rate.
Subcontractors and parts manufacturers are, indeed,
an important part of this play...
I got it. As soon as we get back,
you'll both make a report for me.
Okay.
Your talents will apply perfectly.
Choose the method yourself.
Just... refrain from breaking people's backs.
This time, be careful, in every way.
No need to teach me... Mr. Tsugawa, I will never let down the most precious of my clients.
Sato has only his union behind him,
but his ambitions are already rather councilor's.
One good scandal should be enough
to bring him back to earth.
Seems like this guy really pissed you off...
Right... Once "Showa" sees how fervently we sort everything out,
they won't even remember what "Taihei" is.
Since the self-restrictions were placed,
the production has almost stopped.
And it seems, that soon it'll stop completely.
But the situation might improve too.
I don't want to say anything indecent about Showa company, to which I am indebted...
I always looked forward to meeting with them before.
In that case, what's your opinion on Showa's decision to continue assembling vehicles in America without lines relocation?
What did you say?
Now's not the time for jokes!
I'm told the Showa's union is unanimously against this decision. Am I being deceived?
No... At the moment,
that is the current state of affairs.
Well then, don't you get that without access to parts from Japan, your assembly lines out there are useless?
It is thanks to the individual subcontractors like us,
Japanese cars are so popular and cheap!
But the way you want it done,
newly produced parts won't be able to leave Japan!
There are certain loopholes...
According to current restrictions,
if at least 50% of the parts are manufactured locally,
the vehicle is not considered imported
and parts are not being banned.
But even so... Half of the companies will be unwanted.
What should we produce then?
Do I... Have to find money
to relocate my whole factory now?
Ms. Matsumoto,
for small subcontractors like us, this is vital!
Can't Taihei, by any chance,
find some new work for us before it's too late?
A new work for car parts manufacturers...
Expropriating poorly managed local manufacturers?
Quite a bold plan, I must say.
Mikawa, you understand that this course calls for some sharp practice, don't you?
That's exactly why I chose it.
Showa is all about bold actions!
And what makes it especially good -
it is the cheapest of all!
But at the same time, to get this plan going, huge investments are needed at first.
Such investments are not a big deal for Showa! Why won't you let me handle this personally?
You can't make an omelet without breaking eggs.
You are eager to act, just as always.
Alright, be ready for some private property retrieval US trip.
Got it!
Ms. Matsumoto, you have something to offer too?
Yes. My proposal is also
about expanding Showa's manufacture in America.
And instead of buying, with its own manufactures, the company could obtain parts with other ways, described in this research.
So, what conclusion did you come to?
Color TVs were the subject
of similar trade frictions a few years ago.
Japanese manufacturers then also relocated their production and found themselves at a crossroad.
As a result, to this day,
color TV export to America remains very low.
Most of the companies have expanded their production
by absorbing parts manufacturers.
Thus, it seems, that time the parts subcontractors located here didn't have any problems surviving.
And even when America
has opened its own TV production line,
we could quickly convert our lines
to VTR production and save a lot of effort.
VTRs came in like a sort of pinch hitters to replace the demanded player at the time of need.
But no pinch hitter of that kind might appear in the automobile industry, isn't it?
Exactly. TVs, unlike automobiles, do not consist of such an off scale number of parts.
The number of subcontractors was also fewer, so this time parts manufacturers won't make it out so easily.
You were persuading Hayate
to relocate their production to the homeland.
But for Showa you do the opposite.
This is suspicious...
Hayate had much fewer production facilities, the relocation of which didn't cause that much trouble.
I got it. You say we should stick to the current course
to break through the sanctions?
Yes. With the help of Ms. Yukie
and the archive manager, Mr. Yuki, if you want me to,
I may come up with a new joint business plan for the company and its subcontractors.
I understand. If you can, please do so.
Okay!
So we are saving the local small businesses now?
Makes sense. These guys are always the most vulnerable.
But don't you think that secretly deciding the fate of someone else's company is a bit overconfident?
Besides, we have no idea
how the people working there feel...
Chairman Sato! You have always been against this nonsense! Why did you suddenly change your mind?
For so long you've been convincing us this is wrong, and now, all of a sudden, you start supporting it!
It's not exactly the opposite,
so there's nothing to explain...
We may be a union, but the international economic laws are for everyone to obey, and we are no exception!
Don't tell me...
Did the company just bribe you to get out of their way!?
What are you talking about?
Some things are just good and some are not!
I'm sure the contents of this envelope
will make quite a view for your eyes...
What could it be?
Showa Labor Union chairman:
The spicy and colorful story of money, lust and abuse of authority!
Damn swindler!
I couldn't care less about what you think of me...
But if you don't cooperate, be prepared that tomorrow 50 000 people will enjoy this article.
Everyone around will know about the scandal involving the labor union chairman, aspiring to be elected as the councilor.
Can you imagine how happy the paparazzi will be?
We are grateful to Taihei Company for all the efforts, but the further production expansion will be executed
according to the plan
provided by the Goyo Business Committee.
What did you say?!
Are you saying our plan was not sagacious enough?
No, they both were equally effective. It's just...
Just what's the reason then?
Both plans involved
the local subcontractor companies takeover.
In fact, you both chose North Carolina for it. To give you the idea, how similar they are.
You found this manufacturer too...
The deciding factor was the cost.
The material base will be provided by the agricultural machinery factory, which is about to go bankrupt.
What the...
This manufacturer will be stolen away right under our noses by another Japanese company!?
Getting in touch is all that matters.
Well, the alternative plan was interesting too. Ms. Matsumoto from Taihei proposed a joint affair with subcontractors.
Our company found this plan quite remarkable as well.
Therefore, we wish to continue working with Taihei company, hoping for a productive cooperation in the future.
Rather than hoping in the future,
why don't you right start now?
Ms. Matsumoto, I hope you don't mind that I read your report too. Have to say, this is indeed an outstanding work.
Showa is usually quite sluggish with the new ideas.
But with you in their staff, the company might change for good.
Mr. Gondo! Please restrain from insults here!
Don't mind me, I'm just thinking out loud.
How should I know...
I heard that the new the factory owner is some Japanese.
North Carolina, USA
Seems like from now on we'll be manufacturing Japanese car parts here. That's definitely not something I saw coming of.
I also heard that even if you are in any way deficient,
the owner will still hire you.
But aren't Japanese managers
treat their workers rather like slaves?
If they try to, I'll enslave their company myself!
Well, in that case our union will intercede.
They will come up with something.
If they underpay me a single cent, they'll be sorry!
Whatever is ahead, the Japanese are bound to see we don't do business here the way they are used to.
Although the manager and the boss were discarded,
we still acquired a lot of valuable experience and information.
Go on, go on!
This evening we'll celebrate no matter what!
Ms. Yukie, there's nothing to celebrate. We just lost to the Goyo Committee and yielded them a perspective project.
And you aren't upset?
That's right. This time they just were better.
But the fact that our cars are now being completely assembled outside of Japan is a general success.
Isn't it wonderful that people of different cultures,
languages, and skin colors will now work together to create something wholesome for everyone?
If you put it that way...
However, a few years later, when all Japanese manufacturers will switch their production to on-site manufacturing,
the supply will one day exceed demand and the market will suffer the cars oversupply. Ms. Sawako...
When that happens, they will once again need your help.
Today I pray with all my heart that your business style
would never change, no matter what!
IMF - The International Monetary Fund
in the period between 1981 and 1984 has also placed some restrictions on exports from Japan to the United States.
Soon enough, cars produced on their continent became available to American buyers.
Over these four years, the price of all new cars in America has risen by 50% on average.
If only the export self-restrictions weren't placed, the price increase would've hardly exceeded 27%.
As a result, buyers overpay for cars has reached an astronomical amount - more than $170 billion.
Converting this sum into yen at that time's exchange rate,
it's approximately 4 trillion yen.
In other words,
the buyers were overpaying one trillion yen per year.
In the next episode
WTF, I'm not spoiling the next ep for you
Driving down the midnight highway
Mayonaka no highway
I'm crossing through my memories
yokogitte yuku Memories
Just tonight I beg you not to speak
Tada damatta mama ano hi~
Eye to eye, we stare at each other
Eye to eye mitsume teta
Some nostalgic love song
Natsukashī Love song
Slowly flowing out from the radio
nagareta From the radio
Somehow it feels so dense
Tojikometa
Although in this darkness
It's only two of us: me and my sadness
kanashimi o tataku yō ni
Oh baby play for me!
Oh baby play for me
Soul music
Sweet soul music
Soul music Sweet soul music
Stay with me
Let me hear you
setsunaku kika sete
Sweet soul music,
I love you!
Sweet soul music I love you
While you gently continue to sing
yasashiku utatte