On the court, everyone
Aim for the Ace!
is alone, all alone.
My love
and my pain
nobody understands them.
The shining wind blows.
The sun beats down.
With rose petals on my lips
I leap forth.
Just like the white ball.
Serve! Smash! Volley!
Do your best!
Ace! Ace! Ace!
Aim for the Ace!
The Cinderella of the Tennis World
Episode 1
I love green apples!
I also love the desolate autumn sea,
and the always too slow clock secured in the school tower.
Anyway!
This is Nishi High School,
a co-ed prefectural.
I'm a first-year student here.
And of course, I'm a girl!
I guess I should add one more thing,
our school has the best
tennis team in the prefecture.
And at the risk of embarrassing myself,
I should add that I am a member as well.
It was in! Her lethal smash!
Eh? Did you think that was me?
I'm not her, unfortunately!
This is 11th grader, Ryuzaki Reika.
All the students adore her.
Madame Butterfly,
that's what everyone calls her.
Not only is she beautiful,
but when it comes to tennis,
she's a star player in our league.
She's the reason why there are
so many new tennis players this year.
I'm one of them as well.
Imagine the court as a flower garden, then Ms. Ryuzaki would be
a lovely, graceful butterfly, flitting in the air.
Hiromi!
Hey, Hiromi!
What is it, Maki?
What shall we have after school today,
udon or hamburgers?
This rather indelicate girl next to me
is Aikawa Maki.
She's my best friend.
Did you say something?
I didn't say a word!
And here I am, Oka Hiromi!
Fifteen years old and full of dreams.
Born under the sign of Scorpio.
All right, last 30!
These are the 100 swings.
We finish each day this way.
It's so hard!
Oka?
Your racket isn't properly facing the ball.
Yes, I'll be careful.
Even the hardest parts
of the training are fun.
Ah, yes!
She's our captain, 12th grader Hoshino Miho.
In addition to Madame Butterfly, we have three more mentors, advising the new players.
2nd year students Miya Mariko, Wakatsuki Aoi,
and Otowa Kyoko.
They are not only the girls' team's seniors,
they are also the school's varsity team members.
But the amazing Madame Butterfly is the ace!
That's all for today!
First-years dismissed.
Okay!
Hey Hiromi, udon or hamburgers?
Udon!
All right! Let's go!
What a shame. The udon-stand is closed for the day.
Being on the tennis team makes me so happy.
Me too. Let's go get hamburgers then.
What makes Madame Butterfly such a star?
Because she's Madame Butterfly.
We could never hope to be in her league.
Come on Hiromi,
or the hamburger place will close too.
Hey, did you notice?
Today, Madame Butterfly gave me some advice!
I noticed, and it's not fair.
You were playing poorly on purpose weren't you?
No way! I wouldn't do that, Maki!
Oh yeah? So anyway,
how about those hamburgers?
Please, grant me the blessing
of her advice again tomorrow.
Forget that.
How come?
Oh you don't know? The seniors have been watching over us all this time,
but that's only because
the new coach has been delayed.
But they say he'll be here tomorrow.
That means that,
Madame Butterfly won't…
Doesn't look likely.
When the coach gets here,
juniors will play with juniors and seniors with seniors.
They will no longer have time to tend to us.
My rosy life is going straight down the pits.
I wish that coach wasn't coming.
Madame Butterfly!
It's really her!
And her followers, the varsity team members!
We're in trouble!
Well, making a side trip?
No, that's…
Instead of wasting time,
you first-years should be reading rule books—
Otowa.
We're here to discuss the next
district tournament, are we not?
Please be seated.
Yes.
So, shall we start, Wakatsuki?
Our new coach will be arriving tomorrow.
The district tournament is coming up soon.
His first task will be to choose the varsity members
to represent the school for it.
How about hamburgers?
Let's go.
Hey Maki, playing tennis isn't easy.
Why?
Because if you went at it seriously,
you wouldn't even have time for coffee.
Come on, that's only if you're playing professionally,
and we don't plan to become pros, are we?
That's right.
We're a whole, whole other case.
Other case!
See you tomorrow!
Adieu!
Maki's chit-chat sure tires me out sometimes.
Madame Butterfly!
Sorry, everybody calls you that,
it just slipped out…
I seem to be running into you a lot today, Oka.
Yes, is your district tournament meeting over?
Yes.
I must be going.
Excuse me, my name is Ryuzaki.
Is my racket ready?
Ryuzaki, one moment please.
As expected of the prefecture's leading sports store.
Lots of expensive rackets.
I'm terribly sorry.
I know we promised you'd have it by this time,
but could you wait just one more hour?
A whole hour?
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Now I'm in a fix.
It's okay!
I can pick it up for you!
But then you'd be late.
It's okay!
My house is nearby,
so I won't be late getting home.
I can bring the racket tomorrow.
I would appreciate that, then.
One hour, I can take my time.
Oops, it's upside down!
What a cute uniform.
Ryuzaki!
Ryuzaki Reika
of Nishi High School!
Yes!
I'm sorry to make you wait.
Thank you.
Are you Ryuzaki?
Are you the Nishi ace, Ryuzaki Reika?
Well, don't you know anything about tennis?
I guess you're a beginner.
The racket must be just for show.
How can you not know Madame Butterfly
from Nishi High School?
"Madame Butterfly"?
I'm referring to Ryuzaki Reika.
You should go to the next district tournament.
Then you'll see how sensational is her play.
Excuse me.
How crude! How can he not know Madame Butterfly!?
Bonehead, bumpkin, cheeseburger!
He was looking!
Thank you, Oka—?
It's Hiromi!
Thank you, Hiromi.
Hiromi, look at Todo playing, what an ace he is!
Well, well, her eyes are glued to Madame Butterfly.
Since the moment you met Madame Butterfly,
I guess you're not a Todo's admirer anymore?
Is Todo here?
Over there.
Todo is so great.
You're actually rather fickle, aren't you?
I've never spoken to him,
but he's the student council president, and the boy's tennis team ace.
Todo is so great.
But Madame Butterfly is even greater than great.
To think, I'm surrounded by all these great people.
Those are the greatest things
one could ever ask for, Hiromi.
Please let it be this way forever.
Boys and girls teams, fall in!
Let me introduce!
The new coach of our tennis club,
Coach Munakata.
Aim for the Ace!
- Fight!
- Fight! Fight!
Fight...
My legs are sore and my arches hurt.
Twenty laps on the first day,
what a Demon Coach!
Let's go have some udon,
maybe it'll make our legs feel better.
But you know, the coach
is really a pretty cool guy.
What's wrong, Hiromi?
You haven't spilled a word!
Hey now, what's with the long face?
Sometimes your weird mood swings can be too much!
Was there something that happened?
You're hopeless.
Really, I do look depressed.
And I was so happy before.
Of all people,
why did he have to be our coach?
Well, that racket must be just for show.
You seem like a total poser to me!
Had I known he is our coach,
I'd never call that man a poser.
Now I have to see him everyday!
I'm so depressed!
I'm going to have to quit tennis!
Goemon, don't get so cheeky!
It was his fault! He thought I was Madame Butterfly!
I'm not responsible!
No way I'll give up
on this wonderful tennis club!
You know what, Hiromi,
he really is a Demon Coach.
A Demon Coach?
I'm late because it was my turn to sweep the class!
That Demon Coach will kill me
if I don't hurry to the court!
Is that you, Maki?
Hiromi, why aren't you outside?
It's terrible, that Demon Coach is torturing Madame Butterfly!
What's wrong?
Is that all you've got, Ryuzaki?
That guy is a demon. A true demon. Demon Coach!
Hey, Ozaki. Munakata is tough, isn't he?
Yes, but after all Munakata is a Davis Cup champion…
Nishi High Tennis Club's future looks thrilling.
Let's see how he manages the team
for the upcoming district tournament.
Madame Butterfly!
Are you all right?
Thank you.
Hiromi, where are you going?
Treating Madame Butterfly like that!
Is there a problem?
Well, and... well, I know!
I thought I should apologize to you, for yesterday!
I hate him! Men that only act
from a position of strength are worst of all!
I completely understand.
You go to chew him out,
but end up apologizing.
Hiromi, you're such a child after all.
Don't talk like that, you stupid!
I'll start crying again!
All players bring your racket and get on the court!
First-years fall in!
All right! First-years,
say your names and step forward one at a time.
What's wrong? Come forward!
Hey, do as the coach says!
Yes! Tsuoka Akiko!
All right, get this ball!
You, watch the ball!
Okay, next!
Onoda Hiroko!
Kikuta Aya!
Next!
Tsuino Tsubako!
Kida Chizu!
Next!
Mayama Sumie!
Todo, what's Coach Munakata trying to do?
I'm not sure, but it's not
just special training.
Looks as if he's testing each of them.
Madame Butterfly, I've never seen a coach like him before!
Neither have I.
There's the district tournament coming up,
why is he wasting so much time on the first-years?
Playing at the Davis Cup doesn't necessarily mean
that he's a good coach.
Okay, next.
Aikawa Maki!
Maki!
All right!
Okay, next!
Yes!
Oka Hiromi!
I won't give up!
This Demon Coach!
I'll get even with you,
for Madame Butterfly!
I won't give up!
Hiromi, don't let him beat you!
Goemon's
bed
Goemon, he beat me.
That Demon Coach's ball, it seems,
was just out of my racket's reach.
I will now announce the 5 varsity team members
playing in the coming tournament.
12th grade, Captain Hoshino Miho.
Yes.
11th grade, Ryuzaki Reika.
Also in 11th grade, Miya Mariko.
Yes.
Another 11th grader, Wakatsuki Aoi.
The announcement is just a formality.
Everybody already knows
who the five varsity players are.
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
And finally…
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Miya Mariko
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
10th grade, Oka Hiromi.
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
Wakatsuki Aoi
Otowa Kyoko
Oka Hiromi
That is all.
The varsity team will undergo rigorous training,
for the district tournament.
If I called your name,
be on the court in five minutes.
We'll start practice.
Excuse me, Coach Munakata.
Since you've just arrived,
you might not be familiar with our team.
There's been a mistake.
A mistake? What do you mean?
Instead of Oka Hiromi,
Otowa Kyoko should be the fifth player.
That's right!
We five, including Otowa,
are the tennis club's best members.
Not only that, Coach,
Oka is still just a beginner at tennis!
I am the coach!
My choice was Oka Hiromi.
There was no mistake.
That unruly Oka girl,
she must have offered something to Coach Munakata.
She offered him something?
Did she offer him something?
No way, I didn't! Never!
You're wrong!
Hiromi would never do that!
Madame—
Ms. Ryuzaki!
I didn't know you and the coach were so close, Oka!
Oka Hiromi is appointed as a representative tennis player in the district tournament.
Her seniors treat her coldly.
Even the beautiful and amiable Madame Butterfly won't talk to her.
When Hiromi tries to decline the position,
Coach Munakata refuses to listen to her.
Next time on Aim for the Ace!
"You're the One!"
Hiromi's little heart rolls like a raft
on a frightfully swirling dark current.
On the tennis court at sunset
I saw a pathetic broken tennis racket.
On the tennis court, late at night
I saw a girl who was always crying.
Her initials, written in tears, were H.H.H.O.
The burning love
and the burning tomorrow…
On the white tennis court.
Ah, on the tennis court.