On the court, everyone
Aim for the Ace!
is alone, all alone.
My love
and my pain
nobody understands them.
The shining wind blows.
The sun beats down.
With rose petals on my lips
I leap forth.
Just like the white ball.
Serve! Smash! Volley!
Do your best!
Ace! Ace! Ace!
Aim for the Ace!
You're the One!
Episode 2
Wait…
Well...
Please believe me,
I did not bribe the coach!
I don't understand why he chose me either!
That's your problem.
Don't involve me.
Even Madame Butterfly
doesn't care about me anymore.
Not necessarily.
Madame Butterfly often seems cool and aloof like that.
Today, we'll work with
the first-years on tennis fundamentals.
Yes!
This coach is the cause of it all.
He's the one who appointed me to varsity.
All right! Five meters beyond the net.
Make this baseline your target.
Hey, don't forget to stay in form!
Aren't we district-level players?
We shouldn't have to be "working on our form".
It's fine. We get to watch a certain someone try
and fail to impress the coach.
Hey, Oka! Pay attention!
Yes!
Okay, rotate!
Madame Butterfly.
Okay, do a set of ten, then rotate.
Coach Munakata!
What is it?
Why did you select me?
I'm only in the 10th grade.
I can't be Otowa's replacement in the tournament!
Not only that,
I'm a complete beginner at tennis.
I can't even play in a match.
I can't do it!
So?
So, I'm asking you
to withdraw my appointment!
No. It's already been decided.
Coach, you just don't understand!
Nishi has 5 key tennis players:
Captain Hoshino Miho,
Madame Butterfly,
Wakatsuki Aoi, Miya Mariko,
and Otowa Kyoko.
These are the five. It's always been that way!
These are the ones who took Nishi to the heights of tennis fame.
What you're doing will ruin Nishi's tennis reputation!
Have you had your say?
Okay, back to practice then!
It's student council president Todo,
and tennis team captain, Ozaki.
Aren't you the new varsity member
for the district tournament, Oka Hiromi?
No!
I'm not the one!
She's the first-year
Coach Munakata picked out.
But I hear that she's a just a beginner.
What is Munakata trying to do?
What a shock.
Wait, Oka!
Where did you sneak out
on your own amidst practice?
Or maybe you think appointment to varsity is so natural, you don't even have to bother?
I know why you left,
you ran after Coach Munakata.
Well… I had to ask him something!
Ask him something?
Really?
Next she'll be made captain of the team.
I know, right?
Look how innocent she pretends to be.
Ask him something, she says.
Hiromi!
Hiromi, I've been looking for you everywhere.
Now, put this on.
You'll catch a cold.
Maki, I was getting so cold here.
Of course, silly.
You take everything too seriously.
After that, Maki and I
ate three hamburgers each
and carefully mapped out our plan.
Our plan was to make the demon coach
withdraw me from the varsity team.
Basically, we'd wait for him
to head home the next evening
then the two of us would work to lodge a firm protest.
Then we said our usual goodbyes
at our usual flower shop.
Goemon, how do I look?
Pretty cool, right?
Your little Hiromi is finally getting
her happy school life back starting tomorrow.
And I'm sure Madame Butterfly will become my friend again.
Bravo!
Sorry, Goemon!
Maki, I'm counting on you tonight.
I know that!
Come on, Maki!
Look at her, running around like she hasn't a clue.
It's pathetic to watch!
She's pretending she belongs on varsity.
I've had all I can take.
Same here.
Coach Munakata!
Please give it to me straight.
Why did you choose that first-year Oka instead of me?
My techniques are far better than Oka's!
I think so too!
Me too!
You may be right.
Then why wasn't I chosen for varsity?
You don't know?
You really have no idea?
I don't know! Please tell me!
Work it out on your own.
If you still can't figure it out, come see me.
Kyoko!
I don't understand!
Why the first-year and not me?
Madame Butterfly…
Yes. She'll know why.
I don't understand Coach Munakata either,
why she was chosen.
"Coach, you got me in lots of trouble."
Yes, yes. Just like that!
"It's due to my placement on varsity."
Yep.
"The seniors are being unkind to me,
and the first-years refuse to speak to me."
Good!
"I have no desire to be a professional
or play in tournaments,
that wasn't what I joined the tennis club for."
Agreed!
"Coach, this is a cute 15-year old,
who is being pushed to the brink of hell!"
Great! A striking line!
That touched me!
You think so?
Absolutely!
The demon coach
is sure to take back the decision.
Idiot, we'd just picked up all these balls!
How come you screamed like that?
Oka!
Yes!
Starting tomorrow, practice gets tougher. Be ready.
Good.
Now, Hiromi give him that "cute fifteen" line!
Why? Why is it,
when I see his eyes all my words fade away.
You couldn't help it, it was bad timing.
We'll take care of things tomorrow. Don't worry!
I'll talk to him tomorrow.
Leave it all to me.
Madame Butterfly.
Oka.
Y-Yes?
Could you come back to the tennis court again?
Are you ready?
Yes.
Aim for the Ace!
What is Madame Butterfly doing?
Why did she ask Hiromi back to the court?
Madame Butterfly, why are you doing this to me?
You know I'm just a beginner.
If you're angry because I was chosen for varsity
instead of Otowa, please just tell me so!
Tomorrow I'll ask the coach to take me off varsity,
so…
Please, don't give me any more of that cold stare!
I don't understand.
I don't understand why…
Coach Munakata replaced Otowa Kyoko with her?
Oka!
Yes?
Brace yourself for tough practice
if you expect to play in tournaments.
Did you hear that, Maki?
Madame Butterfly…
Madame Butterfly, she actually encouraged me!
Yes, I heard that!
Madame Butterfly took time to actually play with you.
Hooray!
Goemon's
bed
Here for the district tournament
from Nishi High varsity, Oka Hiromi!
Yes, I'm Oka Hiromi!
I look just like Madame Butterfly.
It's great that Madame Butterfly
isn't mad at you.
Now Hiromi, are you going to
give varsity a try?
Yes.
Silly.
Hey Maki! Let's focus on our backhand today!
I'm all charged up for productive practice.
Suddenly I feel like I'm really representing
Nishi varsity! Just kidding!
Oka,
being on varsity seems to have energized you.
Did something good happen to you?
Well…
It's probably that practice
with Madame Butterfly yesterday.
That's what you're all
pumped up over, isn't it?
Don't make me laugh!
Do you really think Madame Butterfly
would play with beginners?
Madame Butterfly couldn't
understand why the coach chose you.
So she decided to test you out.
In other words, she did it on a whim. Get it?
That's awful.
It was all just a whim?
I was going to give it a chance.
But what Otowa said was…
No, that's not it.
Madame Butterfly did encourage me.
Excuse me, Ms. Ryuzaki!
Did you want something?
No, never mind.
My heart is pounding.
I don't care about fame,
but Madame Butterfly did encourage me.
Is my heart still pounding?
Madame Butterfly and Todo.
It's a good match!
I'll leave them alone.
I see. Coach Munakata still
hasn't explained his choice yet?
There must be something about her
that he can see but we can't.
But what?
What did Coach Munakata see?
I'm beat.
I've been waiting, Oka!
Sorry, you won't mind practicing with me, would you?
Practice with you?
Right, because you're on varsity.
Since you're on varsity and I'm not,
I want you to coach me.
Please do, Oka.
All of us have been waiting for you.
Okay, ready?
Now you'll really see how much I outclass you.
My, you can't return such an easy serve?
Kyoko's smash is as good as always.
She learned it directly from Madame Butterfly.
Do you understand now, Hiromi?
I've mastered Madame Butterfly's
technique better than anyone in Nishi High.
That's horrible!
She's just torturing Hiromi!
What's wrong?
Aren't you on the varsity team?
You intend to represent Nishi
with that technique? How dare you!
Now! Stand up!
We're not done yet!
That's enough.
Don't blemish yourself.
Yes.
Hiromi!
Hiromi! Hiromi!
I don't understand!
Why, I just don't understand!
Why was Oka chosen?
What's wrong with me?
It looks like you haven't figured out why yet.
I don't understand!
I'll tell you then.
Otowa, you're imitating Madame B's tennis.
An imitation remains an imitation forever.
It will never surpass the original.
Understand, Otowa?
I don't want players with crippled potential.
How unbelievably cruel.
That's… so twisted, Coach!
I can't agree with that! I can't!
Then stop imitating, Otowa.
It's not too late to start over.
It makes no sense to me!
I can't understand a word of what you're saying!
Oka, unless I'm mistaken,
I saw something.
You've got it in you.
You probably aren't aware of it.
But one day, without a doubt,
confidence will find you.
Well, Hiromi,
I'll leave your bag and clothes here.
Bye.
You better hurry home and take a bath.
Your face is covered with dirt.
Okay, okay! I won't say anything more.
I'll be going.
How could I have ended up on varsity?
It absolutely can't be!
It can't be!
It can't be possible!
What are you doing out here so late?
Say, are you feeling ill or something?
Todo.
No.
Well, it's nothing!
That startled me!
Why did Todo have to show up now?
It's not fair, not fair at all!
Oh no, did he see my face? Dear me.
How embarrassing!
A thumbtack!
The district tournament is here.
Hiromi has become more stressed.
Todo Takayuki kindly encourages Hiromi.
Then, Madame Butterfly gives her racket to Hiromi.
Go Hiromi! The ball is your opponent!
Next time on Aim for the Ace!
"Tears at the District Qualifiers!"
Hiromi's heart is dashed upon the bright white tennis court.
On the tennis court at sunset
I saw a pathetic broken tennis racket.
On the tennis court, late at night
I saw a girl who was always crying.
Her initials, written in tears, were H.H.H.O.
The burning love
and the burning tomorrow…
On the white tennis court.
Ah, on the tennis court.