On the court, everyone
Aim for the Ace!
is alone, all alone.
My love
and my pain
nobody understands them.
The shining wind blows.
The sun beats down.
With rose petals on my lips
I leap forth.
Just like the white ball.
Serve! Smash! Volley!
Do your best!
Ace! Ace! Ace!
Aim for the Ace!
So that's how it is, Ryuzaki. Got it?
Coach, I refuse!
I can't play doubles in a unbalanced pair.
I'm the one who's unfortunate,
to be put on the same level as Oka.
Yeah, hiya!
Transform!
Fired up! Special Training with a Chill in the Air
Episode 14
What's wrong, Oka?
Do you expect to win the Kanto Tournament like that?
Apologies for my tardiness.
Spare me excuses!
Hurry and get on the court!
Yes.
I'll do my best!
She's irritated.
Because she has to play doubles with someone awful
like me, Madame Butterfly must hate it.
I just need to get better, right, Madame Butterfly?
I can think like that, can't I?
All right.
Let's start the doubles practice.
Hoshino and Miya,
come here and play with Ryuzaki and Oka.
Okay!
All of you should take this seriously.
Oka! If you can't even receive a smash like that,
what are you going to do?
Sorry!
And Ryuzaki, why did you not receive it just now?
That ball could easily be returned.
Being good in defense won't be enough!
Be aware you're playing doubles now!
Okay.
I'm sorry, Madame Butterfly.
These troubles are all my fault.
All right, I'll return it for sure this time!
Oh no.
Darn it!
This is cruel. She's purposely trying to make
Madame Butterfly look bad.
Madame Butterfly oughta be pitied.
There's nothing worse than having a weaker partner.
Even if you say so,
they're continuously attacking Hiromi!
How can Hiromi face that...
Aikawa!
Focusing on one player to ruin their teamwork
is the standard strategy for doubles.
And that's why it's necessary
to find someone who is a close match in doubles.
Oka, you won't return the ball
by just swinging the racket.
Hold with a stronger grip! More confidence!
I know! I know, but what can I do
when I can't hit it the way I want to?
I'm starting, Oka.
Okay.
Returned!
Don't return it straight to opponent!
Okay!
I can't move like I want to.
Ball timings keep eluding me.
What am I even doing? While standing
on the same court as Madame Butterfly.
Even though I do my best, I can't stop it.
I'm sorry, Madame Butterfly!
Even if I take this seriously, it's no use.
Excuse me, I have a headache.
Madame Butterfly!
Oka!
Yes?
I won't give up on you while there's still a chance.
However...
If you give up on yourself, that's it.
Don't forget it.
I'm prepared to thrust you aside at any time.
I'm prepared to thrust you aside.
I'm prepared.
I'm prepared...
Hiromi, it's pointless to be constantly worried about it.
Don't worry, tomorrow Madame Butterfly
will feel better and come back out.
The Queen was just having an off day.
Don't worry.
This is how it's always been, right?
Remember when you lost the racket she gave you,
you returned to the tennis club and she forgave you?
That's different.
Neither in doubles nor in singles
has she ever lost a match before.
But in the Kanto Tournament, she'll lose because of me.
She's very proud and hates to lose more than anyone,
so there's no way she would forgive me.
Hiromi, cheer up, for Goodness sake!
Hey Hiromi, let's pass by Sabu's place.
I got kind of hungry.
You're starving too, aren't you?
Not even a little?
Hiromi.
Hey, here you go!
Hiromi sure is in a difficult position.
It's because she won in the prefecture tournament,
she is put into such cruel retraining so soon!
But trying to reach the same level
as Madame Butterfly is a nonstarter!
And when Madame Butterfly was paired with Hiromi,
she couldn't play up to her real ability.
I wonder why the Coach doesn't have a hint
about a girl's delicacy!
People who don't understand delicacy are the worst!
Yes, that's right, very right.
Sabu, another hamburger, please!
Eh? That's your third now.
Are you fine eating that much?
You'll also dinner when you get home.
Maki, you sure your belly will endure?
I'm a girl!
I hate those who don't understand delicacy!
Tea Salon
You can't break down, Hiromi.
Got it?
Is this dog yours?
Here I go!
Transform!
Little boy, let's cross safely.
Yeah!
Even if I take it seriously, it's still impossible.
Don't forget.
I'm prepared to throw you away at any time.
I'm not crying because I'm sad.
It's because the sea is so beautiful.
But I'm still a Nishi High player.
No matter what Madame Butterfly thinks about me,
no matter what Coach Munakata tells me,
I can't do anything but my best.
I know that clearly.
But...
But if I'm getting close to breaking down again,
Todo, help me!
Aim for the Ace!
Hiromi!
Hiromi, what happened to you yesterday?
I was worried!
I'm sorry.
It's fine, fine.
Now, let's go before we're late.
But is she really going
to the Kanto Tournament in that state?
With such a difference in levels,
that pair will crumble at once.
If they focus on her,
even Madame Butterfly won't be able to do much.
I'm late.
To be fair, that girl...
Here she is.
Kanto Tournament players
have to practice doubles thoroughly today.
The rest will practice individually.
Okay!
Coach!
Yes?
I just received a call from Ms. Ryuzaki.
She doesn't feel well today,
so she'll rest from the practice.
I see.
Rest?
That's not right.
It's not that Madame Butterfly's body is unwell.
She just can't stand playing doubles with me.
And… And…
Coach!
I have a request.
What is it, Otowa?
Will you let me replace Ryuzaki for today
and pair up with Oka for doubles practice?
All right, why not.
Well then, let's start!
It's bad…
Reasoning tells me I have to do my best,
but realistically, when this happens I always hesitate.
I'm trembling already!
Madame Butterfly!
Wait for me, Madame Butterfly!
Oka!
Why are you dawdling there?
The Kanto Tournament won't be so easy!
Yes! I'm sorry!
Listen, Oka!
I'm Madame Butterfly for today,
but don't expect me to take it easy on you.
Okay!
Here I come!
Oka, to the front!
Okay!
That dash is too lousy!
Be more aggressive!
Okay!
Get closer to the net!
Keep an eye on ball!
Okay!
Smash! Get it!
Keep an eye on opponents' movement!
Too bad, too bad!
Otowa is starting it again.
Take a look, it seems like someone
just wasn't made for doubles.
It's no wonder Madame Butterfly needed a break.
Hiromi.
Now, here it comes!
Okay!
What are you doing, Oka?
This is not something you interrupt the play for.
Yes. I'm sorry!
Now, serve the ball.
It's like they're hazing her!
Stop it already!
Stop it! Just stop it!
Stop it, please!
Please!
This is too much for Hiromi!
Coach, please stop this.
Please be considerate!
What I should be considerate of, Aikawa?
What do you mean?
This tournament is not like her previous matches.
Without this much retraining,
there's no point to enter the Kanto Tournament.
Hiromi...
All right, get some rest.
That's all for today.
Dismissed.
Hiromi, pull yourself together.
Look here. This is the Jet Fighter
and this is the Cyborg Hydra!
Here I come, transform!
I will slay the monster!
This is painful.
Since I started playing tennis,
there hasn't been a day this miserable.
Oka.
Midorikawa!
What is it? You look like the world's coming to an end.
You're going to the Kanto Tournament, aren't you?
Yeah.
Looking at your pitiful face, it seems
like Coach Munakata scolded you a fair amount.
But there's not much of a choice.
This time around, it's the Kanto Tournament. It's natural that the training is very harsh.
But Coach Munakata is too cruel!
Cruel?
Madame Butterfly and I
are going to be paired up for doubles.
Isn't that combination unbalanced?
Because of Coach Munakata,
I'll be a burden to Madame Butterfly.
The pride of Nishi High's tennis kingdom,
Madame Butterfly
playing doubles with a first-year
who barely made it through?
One is ahead and the other chases after.
No, about to surpass the one.
It's a norm for them to have a friction.
But you shouldn't expect any sympathy because of it.
That happens because you are capable
of surpassing the partner.
No matter what kind of misery you go through,
isn't that pain for the love of tennis?
The pain of not being able to play tennis
is also a thing in our world.
Look at this!
It will take two full months to recover!
I want you to understand.
I can't even hold a racket because of this pain!
It makes me feel bad
for worrying about such a petty pain.
Compared to her suffering,
I'm fortunate enough just to be able play tennis.
Over a disgracefully small and trivial thing,
I was indecisive, childish, and a straightforward fool!
Midorikawa!
Well... I…
Thank you very much!
It's all right.
But from now on,
please stop speaking poorly of the Coach.
There isn't any better coach than Munakata Jin
in the world.
I know that better than anyone.
Listen, never forget you have a rival who craves
to be coached by Munakata Jin as well, but cannot.
Goemon, Hiromi was a bit too spoiled until now.
When I think about Midorikawa,
my troubles just seem to be silly.
Look at this hand!
My hand looks much better
holding a tennis racket!
This hand... Once this hand takes a hold of the racket,
it will never let go of it!
Thank goodness,
Hiromi is doing well again.
And also…
Madame Butterfly showed up for practice.
More to the front!
All right!
It's all right if I can just play tennis!
This doesn't even count as pain!
When I think about Midorikawa,
I know for certain, I can handle this!
If I break down here,
Midorikawa will mock me!
This is not painful!
She's nothing like she was two days ago.
I wonder how this girl
always keeps picking herself back up.
That's right, Oka.
Do your best!
Once you've endured this training,
you'll be able to play with Ryuzaki in doubles.
And there's a target for you too, Ryuzaki.
In order to rise, to overcome this,
you must first endure this retraining, Oka!
Jin, I hope that helped you a bit.
Student CouncIl Room
I'm sorry! I caused all this mess!
Todo!
Even though our time together was short, it was fun.
I wonder if Todo is in.
Oh yeah, I found something unusual.
I'll only reveal it to you.
Coach Munakata and Kaga High's Midorikawa Ranko
are actually siblings!
Siblings?
Yes. Siblings from different mothers.
But from now on, please stop speaking poorly
of Coach Munakata.
There isn't a better coach than Munakata Jin
in the whole world.
Don't forget you have a rival who wants
to get coaching from Munakata Jin, but can't.
Coach Munakata and Midorikawa are siblings.
To Be Continued
In anticipation for the Kanto Tournament,
Hiromi and Madame Butterfly
are working hard in the doubles training,
but Hiromi's keeps making mistakes.
The troubled Hiromi is watched over kindly by the invincible doubles combination of Todo and Ozaki.
Todo's kind advice lightens Hiromi's heart.
Next time on Aim for the Ace!
"The Secret Behind Their Doubles Pair"
Hiromi's heart that comes back
from destruction, shines like a sunrise!
On the tennis court at sunset
I saw a pathetic broken tennis racket.
On the tennis court, late at night
I saw a girl who was always crying.
Her initials, written in tears, were H.H.H.O.
The burning love
and the burning tomorrow…
On the white tennis court.
Ah, on the tennis court.