On the court, everyone
Aim for the Ace!
is alone, all alone.
My love
and my pain
nobody understands them.
The shining wind blows.
The sun beats down.
With rose petals on my lips
I leap forth.
Just like the white ball.
Serve! Smash! Volley!
Do your best!
Ace! Ace! Ace!
Aim for the Ace!
Tears at the District Qualifiers
Episode 3
What a quiet afternoon,
one can almost hear the flowers blooming,
and the murmur of the rainbow in the fountain.
Aikawa. Aikawa Maki!
Yes! Well, is there something you want?
What happened to Oka?
I don't see her on the court.
Yes, well…
Right, I was supposed to hand you
the note of her sudden injury.
She got hurt so she can't come to practice today.
She got hurt?
Yes, she said it was a serious injury.
Ah, it's nice to have a day without worries.
I think I'll skip practice tomorrow too.
Then that stubborn Demon Coach
won't make me play at the tournament.
Hiromi!
Hi, Maki!
So, have you been practicing hard?
My, why do you have that look on your face?
The coach told me, "Get Oka now!"
Maki, didn't you give him my sudden injury note?
Yes, exactly as you asked!
Well, I'm sorry,
I know this is a bad time to be absent…
But you see,
I cannot play at the tournament in this state.
Oka, is this the said injury?
This red spot?
Well, that's…
Speak up!
Yes! I stepped on a thumbtack!
What?
I know it doesn't look like much,
but it hurts a lot!
So, playing in the tournament is out of the question!
That's enough!
Go get changed!
Okay!
I'm not going to give in!
What arrogance!
Who does he think he is?
How can I go to the tournament?
Oka!
Oka, what are you doing?
It's your turn!
Yes!
Come on, that was just a straight from the net!
I'm sorry!
I'll get the ball.
Look at yourself.
How can you dare show up
for the tournament?
Otowa, well…
the ball…
Oka, what are you doing?
Yes!
Fall in!
Listen up! The essence of any sport
is having a good concentration!
No mindless play from now on!
All right, dismissed.
Dismissed!
Thank you very much!
Oka!
Yes!
Stay here. We'll practice serving and receiving.
What? No way, just me?
No whining!
Maki, help me!
What a turncoat.
Oka!
Hurry up on the court!
It's getting dark!
Okay!
Keep your eyes on the ball! The ball!
Oka, that backhand is useless!
Pay attention!
Okay!
Hiromi, do your best.
Wow, he's being tough.
Idiot! I'm such a bonehead!
In front of Todo and Ozaki, too!
Oh no! Todo is watching my humiliation!
Darn it!
You'll get it now, Demon Coach!
Okay, that's it for today.
Sorry about the wait. Let's go.
- Yes.
- Okay.
Hey, Oka, put the net away, will you.
How cold, they didn't even say goodbye.
Maki!
Hamburgers, let's go!
Hey, don't wolf them down like that.
No whining!
Is what the coach said to me.
What? Is that all?
Sabu, Hiromi is on varsity for the next district match!
That's great!
Not a thing is great about it!
As of now, the ball and my racket never seem to meet.
They manage to handle balls with much smaller bats,
and you have those huge rackets!
Sabu, are you on my side
or are you making fun of me?
No, I'm not making fun of anyone.
But look at it yourself: if you were chosen for it,
you must have some sort of aptitude.
No, not at all!
This coach is just sick in the head!
Don't talk like that!
I'll go see the match and cheer you on.
Well, give it your best.
No, no way! If you come, I'll take a bite out of you!
Relax, I'm not a hamburger!
Not wanting anyone to cheer her on. Weird kid!
I will, I won't, I will, I won't.
I will, I won't, I will.
I won't, I will, I won't.
Hiromi!
What are you doing?
Still thinking about it?
Of course. I figured I could slip away
from that wicked Demon Coach!
Coach Munakata?
He's kind of cool, though.
He may seem a bit cold, but a coach like that
can be a refreshing change.
You traitor. Put yourself in my shoes!
But I do know how you feel.
Maybe I'll do a hunger strike until I'm too sick to play.
A hunger strike?
That's one thing you could never pull off!
Just watch, I'll show you!
Hiromi!
Wait, Hiromi!
Ouch, ouch!
Todo!
It's okay, don't worry.
I shouldn't be napping here anyway.
By the way, I'm sorry.
I overheard you talking.
Oka, Coach Munakata is a reasonable man.
Anyway, you should give it a try, okay?
But…
Don't think about it, just do your best.
That's all you need.
Well, I'm off!
I spoke with him,
I spoke with Todo!
You did it, Hiromi!
Don't talk to me!
My ears will get polluted!
What... Your ears? Why, you!
Well, how about that.
And she was so blue until just a minute ago.
I can't believe I really talked to Todo.
It has to be a good omen.
All right! Nothing can stop me now!
Not good! Practice is starting!
Practice, practice!
Not even one racket left!
Oh my, all the rackets are out for repair,
didn't you know?
For repair?
Some people are rough on them.
Oka, how can you be on varsity
but not have your own racket?
What makes you think you're fit for varsity?
That's too much.
It's not fair to gang up on you.
Hiromi, cheer up!
You've decided to give it a try. Don't let them get you down.
Oka?
Madame Butterfly!
With your strength,
you should use a lightweight racket.
Here, I used to use this racket.
I think it would be right for you.
This is for you, take good care of it.
Madame Butterfly…
So, do your best!
Hiromi!
Madame Butterfly gave me her racket…
I must be dreaming!
Aim for the Ace!
I need a towel!
Ota, do you know where my shoes are?
All of you from Nishi High, please get ready.
Yes!
Hurry up everyone! Don't leave anything here.
Meet me on the tennis court.
Yes!
What's keeping Hiromi?
Madame Butterfly, everything is ready.
Thank you.
Captain, do we have everybody?
Well, Oka isn't here yet!
What? There's just five minutes to find her!
Y-Yes, I'll do it! I'll go!
Hiromi gives me stomach aches at times!
Maki! Hurry up, it's going to start!
That girl! That's supposed to be my line!
Oka, tell me why you were late.
Yes, I overslept.
What? You overslept?
Well, I couldn't sleep last night,
so I was awake until early in the morning.
And then you overslept!
I'm sorry.
I've heard enough of it.
Get ready now!
Yes!
I can't believe it!
Oh my, that racket!
Madame Butterfly!
Otowa!
What's wrong with her?
Why did Madame Butterfly give Oka her racket?
That'll just give her a big head.
All players, please show up on the main court.
All players, please get to the preparatory court.
Hiromi, what's wrong?
I'm cold, I can't stop shivering.
H-Hiromi!
Maki, I don't want to play.
I want to go home.
Don't be silly. You've managed to get this far,
so stick with it, you have to!
All players, please report your presence
and show up on the main court.
Go on, Hiromi!
I'll support you from the stands.
Do your best!
All right. At least I can go home when it's over.
I know I won't win.
I'll just shut my eyes and let it happen,
but, but still…
I'm scared! Going to the guillotine
must've felt like this!
There's nothing more I can say at this point.
Just trust yourself and do your best.
Yes!
Oka!
Listen, forget about your opponent.
Make the ball your only opponent.
Just watch the ball and play.
Just watch the ball…
That's right.
Okay.
I guess right now I can say that,
but I still just want to go home.
Court 1, Oka. Court 2, Ryuzaki.
Court 3, Hoshino.
Court 4, Wakatsuki. Court 5, Miya.
Go!
Fight!
Yes!
Hiromi, go for it!
Hiromi, do your best!
- My, Sabu, you're here?
- You bet! I was worried!
It's a problem if her racket and the ball never meet.
Hiromi, go for it!
Sabu, the audience is only allowed to clap in tennis.
Loud cheering will get you thrown out.
Eh?
Now, look at the court.
Hiromi's opponent looks tough.
She looks tough.
Why did it have to be her?
Best of three set match. Aoba's service!
I guess nothing matters,
since I'll lose anyway.
I want to go home sooner!
Shucks! She scored an ace already!
Service ace, Aoba. 15-0.
Wow, the ball didn't even graze the racket.
I guess she wasn't joking.
30-0.
Hiromi, hang in there.
Hey, hey, hey.
What is it?
Well, excuse my ignorance, but what do those
"Fifteen-Love" and "Thirty-Love" stand for?
Oh my, Sabu, you came to a tennis match
without knowing the rules?
I guess so.
Ah, well then.
Listen, "Fifteen-Love"
would mean "15-0" in Japanese,
the same with "Thirty-Love" standing for "30-0."
Do you understand, Sabu?
30-0? Wow, Hiromi lost that many points already?
I only saw her lose two serves so far.
Idiot! The first point is 15,
the second point is 30 in tennis.
That's how it works!
I see now. Interesting.
She lost a point again.
Now it's 45 to 0.
Wrong again! It's 40 to 0!
That's strange.
The third point should be 45.
It isn't strange.
It's 40. That's the rule!
But think of it...
Be quiet! That's enough.
She'll lose the first game
if she misses one more.
Hiromi, do your best!
She lost the first game.
15-0.
30-0.
40-0.
AOBA
NISHI
15-0.
AOBA
NISHI
30-0.
40-0.
AOBA
NISHI
It goes on for 3 games already,
she is losing with a shutout.
While our other players are winning flawlessly.
You're the only one here with that unsightly play.
AOBA
NISHI
The first set is over.
Game count, six games to Love.
I couldn't score a single point
in 6 games of the first set!
Coach, everybody except Oka won their first set straight.
Everyone except Oka.
I understand.
I want to go home. Go home...
The sooner the better.
Todo!
Oka, go for it.
Anyway, you should give it a try.
Don't think about it,
just do your best. Your best.
Give it your best!
Your best!
That's right.
Why am I treating myself like this?
Be it because I'm losing,
be it because I want to go home,
I shouldn't let myself overreact and get upset!
This will be like at practice.
That's it! I'll just make it one of my practices.
I always enjoy them!
I'll try my best
and enjoy my tennis to the fullest!
That's the way, Oka.
Make the ball your only opponent!
Watch the ball and go straight to it!
That's it! The ball!
Hit the ball!
Give it everything!
That's it!
She did it! She hit ball!
Be quiet! It was out!
But she hit the ball.
It went outside the line,
so it was out.
I see.
Coach, if Oka loses this set,
the match is over for her.
I know.
I hit the ball!
Out or in or home run or whatever,
I really hit it and that's all that matters!
Here it comes!
My opponent is the ball!
I'll just watch the ball and hit it!
That's it!
My leg! My leg won't move!
Hiromi suffers a leg cramp during the match and falls down on the tennis court.
Otowa Kyoko expresses
her contempt for Hiromi,
by having Munakata arrange a match between them.
The winner will get the pass
to the next match.
Next time on Aim for the Ace!
"Confrontation at the Tennis Court"
Hiromi tries her best.
Her heart ablaze!
On the tennis court at sunset
I saw a pathetic broken tennis racket.
On the tennis court, late at night
I saw a girl who was always crying.
Her initials, written in tears, were H.H.H.O.
The burning love
and the burning tomorrow…
On the white tennis court.
Ah, on the tennis court.