On the court, everyone
Aim for the Ace!
is alone, all alone.
My love
and my pain
nobody understands them.
The shining wind blows.
The sun beats down.
With rose petals on my lips
I leap forth.
Just like the white ball.
Serve! Smash! Volley!
Do your best!
Ace! Ace! Ace!
Aim for the Ace!
It's the second set.
If they lose this set, those two will…
What? There's nothing to worry about. It's fine.
No, Ozaki, didn't you notice
that last serve of the second set by Izuka?
The one that looked like a tornado?
Yes, a Tornado Serve.
From what I could tell,
it looked like a modified twist serve.
The way she hit the ball also attests to that.
But all that massive rotation
can't be caused by a standard twist serve.
I see. It must be a new technique
based on the twist serve.
But what if they keep using that serve?
It'll be fine.
All right. Oka, do your best!
Episode 17
Roaring! The Evil Twist Serve
Second set, play!
Service: Showa High, Izuka!
Oka!
Yes!
It's coming. Prepare yourself.
Okay!
All right!
I'm going to do it!
After losing the first set,
no matter what it takes, I must win this set!
Here!
Oh no, it's that serve again.
Whatever!
Like I would get scared over that!
Looks like she can't handle my Tornado Serve yet.
There's no way you'll receive a ball like this!
Oh no, she's going to use the same serve again.
You have to be kidding me.
I won't fall for the same move again!
Here!
Oka, it's up to you!
Keep your eyes on the ball!
40-0!
Your worries were justified after all, Todo.
At this rate, stopping that Tornado Serve is the top priority for the Nishi High's pair of Oka - Ryuzaki.
It will be the deciding factor
in points' distribution, Mr. Munakata.
Are you all right, Oka?
Yes. But I'm sorry I fell for the same serve twice.
It's all right. The second set has only
just started. Just calm down, all right?
Okay!
I will not lose to that serve again!
I won't lose!
30-0!
Oka, if you don't learn to receive the Tornado Serve,
there is nothing I can do on my part.
Get up, Oka! You have to do something
to break through!
This time…
This time,
I'll get it! I'll get it!
Maki, you want to make an order?
Oh my, it's been 30 minutes since the match started.
Hey Maki, stop being so stubborn
and go cheer them on.
Think of poor Hiromi.
Be quiet!
I don't want to ever see Hiromi
getting crushed by the Tornado Serve!
Maki, you're going after all!
I'm telling you to shut up time after time!
It's to toilet.
Game count: 1-0 for Showa High.
I'm sorry for getting shut out.
Nothing to worry, it's just one game.
Don't mind it.
Instead, it's your serve now.
Focus on it, Oka.
Okay.
I have Madame Butterfly here with me,
so I have to do my best!
I have a valuable ally,
Madame Butterfly herself!
15-0!
Thank you, Madame Butterfly.
All right.
I will definitely take this game!
30-0!
All right! Keep going like that!
- Look out for Ryuzaki!
- Okay!
I have to make this a tie now,
to crush them after that.
Game count: 1-1!
What you'd expect from Madame Butterfly!
Now it's a tie!
All right, keep it up, keep it up!
We lost one game.
Winning one set doesn't mean you can relax.
Yes, we're sorry.
In the next game,
the rookie Oka will be up front.
Target her with Continuous Attack right away.
You must win.
- Yes, we understand.
What are you going to do, Coach Munakata?
There's nothing much to say.
- Play a good match!
- Okay.
Go then.
Ryuzaki!
I leave Oka to you.
I understand.
Here I go!
Okay!
There's only one target, the rookie!
Oka!
All right, we caught her!
Hurry up, I'm worried about poor Hiromi!
It's impossible with this traffic jam.
That's why I told you to go sooner.
It's pointless saying that now.
I didn't want to see Hiromi's losing match back then!
Fine, I'll just walk.
It's dangerous to get out now!
Leave me alone!
See, it's moving again.
30-0!
One more!
I will not let you Continuously Attack Oka.
Great! She stopped the Continuous Attack on Oka.
Way to go, Madame Butterfly!
Thank you!
Maki, your scarf! Scarf!
Leave it in the car!
I'm sorry Hiromi, for leaving you alone.
I wonder how the match has gone so far.
It's a close battle, Aikawa.
They have deuce after deuce and it's suffocating.
Just one more point.
They need it to take this set.
Hiromi…
Hiromi!
Do your best!
You have to do your best, Hiromi!
Hiromi!
Aim for the Ace!
Deuce!
End of second set.
Game count: 6-4 for Nishi High,
Ryuzaki - Oka pair!
Great! They beat the Continuous Attack!
Hiromi, you did so well!
Maki, what happened?
They took the second set, so it's a tie now!
So they need just one more set?
Yes, then they'll win! They will win!
You did very well
enduring that Continuous Attack, Oka.
And Ryuzaki was spectacular, as always.
The third set will be fun to watch,
Coach Munakata.
Oka.
Yes?
You did very well back there.
I owe that to you blocking their Continuous Attack.
Third set is the hardest.
Let's do our best.
Yes.
But Izuka will start the next set
with her Tornado Serve again...
It's fine, Oka.
I will receive the Tornado Serve.
You are to guard the front
and that will suffice.
Okay!
That's right.
Don't forget the most powerful weapon -
the cooperation of two partners.
No matter what Igarashi's plans are.
Continuous Attack is broken,
but don't lose your nerve.
We still have our Tornado Serve.
Oka will probably be up front
and the service receiver will be Ryuzaki.
Ryuzaki?
That's right.
Even if it's Ryuzaki,
she can't withstand the Tornado Serve.
Push it with Tornado Serve.
Got it, Izuka, Kihara?
-Yes!
Three set match.
Final set, play!
It's just as we planned.
Tornado Serve!
15-0!
Even Madame Butterfly can't return it!
That's impossible,
it's Madame Butterfly after all!
Here it comes, Ms. Ryuzaki!
30-0!
This is bad.
She missed two service aces already.
Can the Tornado Serve be stopped at all?
If Madame Butterfly can't return it…
No, that isn't possible. She'll definitely do it.
This is unforgivable!
Unforgivable!
30-15!
Madame Butterfly returned the Tornado Serve!
There's no way she could stop the Tornado Serve.
No way… That was just luck.
It must be luck!
It'll be the same every time.
The spin of the ball slows down
as it hits the bound and jumps.
That moment you smash it and deliver...
the fatal blow!
All right! As long as the Tornado Serve is harnessed,
even Showa High is helpless.
But the Tornado Serve was coached by Igarashi.
They should be wary.
Even with Tornado Serve defeated,
the game isn't decided.
Isn't that right, Izuka?
Yes! But Coach...
Keep it together, Izuka.
You haven't lost yet.
Still!
Kihara, you calm down too!
Listen, the opponent has one more weakness.
Weakness?
Yes, and you will exploit that weakness,
using your Tornado Smash.
Weakness…
Tornado Smash?
- Okay!
There is only one target - Oka Hiromi!
Do it now!
Tornado Smash!
15-0!
What happened to Hiromi just now?
No idea.
Did you see that Todo? That technique is similar
to the Tornado Serve.
Yeah, it totally is.
Tornado Smash, then?
Yes.
It's bad this time!
They're planning to continuously attack Oka
with that smash!
Darn it! Why are they always
aiming at Hiromi?
It hurts Maki, please let go!
I won't forgive them!
Are you all right, Oka?
Pull. Pull yourself together!
That smash is similar to the Tornado Serve,
when it rebounds and its spin slows,
you are to smash it back at them.
You can do it, Oka.
Fly! You have to fly, Oka! Okay?
Fly? Fly and smash the ball after it rebounds.
I see!
Jump!
I can't!
My legs won't move the way I want them to!
You can do it, Oka!
Get up and fly!
Hiromi, come on, get up!
Get up, Oka!
Hiromi is already exhausted.
Oka, if you don't get up, what will I...
What will I do by myself?
Please stand, for both of our sakes.
Madame Butterfly is crying.
It doesn't matter if you cry.
When you solve your shared problems together,
that's when you can become a great pair.
Do your best,
Ryuzaki,
Oka!
Get up!
I have to fly!
Game count: 2-3,
Nishi High's lead!
You did it, Hiromi!
Game count: 3-4!
Kihara, why did you bump into me?
You're the one who got in the way!
That was my perfect chance ball!
It came closer to me,
that's why I called you back!
All right, the opponent's pace is falling apart.
Oka, that's just like how we were in the first set.
Listen, let's give it our everything, until the end.
Yes!
40-30!
Oka, it's match point.
Yes!
The last…
the last…
this last ball!
Ace!
It's an ace!
A service ace!
Game set!
Set count: 2-1 for Nishi High's pair,
Ryuzaki - Oka!
Hiromi!
Hiromi, congratulations!
Bravo, Madame Butterfly!
I was mistaken.
You have trained a good pair of players.
It'll go even smoother from now on.
As expected from you, Munakata.
Oka, you did quite well.
We really did win, didn't we?
That's right, we won, Hiromi!
Thank you, Madame Butterfly!
To Be Continued
"You can't rely on quick feet alone when playing tennis."
Hiromi, whose specialty is running,
was warned about this by Coach Munakata.
But right now Hiromi can't find
a solution besides more practice.
While in that mindset, a mysterious girl appears before Hiromi.
She has a weird laugh
and challenges Hiromi to a match.
Next time on Aim for the Ace!
"Fight the Black Spy!"
Not knowing her opponent is a spy, Hiromi's soul
trembles violently as she hits the sharp ball.
On the tennis court at sunset
I saw a pathetic broken tennis racket.
On the tennis court, late at night
I saw a girl who was always crying.
Her initials, written in tears, were H.H.H.O.
The burning love
and the burning tomorrow…
On the white tennis court.
Ah, on the tennis court.