The most precious moment in life is the time of taking a decision.
The Pacific War taught us the preciousness of peace.
But also bequeathed to us
numerous lessons on how to live.
Animentary
Decision
Wisdom is your weapon
Remember to use your head
Leave all your worries aside,
If you are a man
One decision is enough
To make others cry or laugh
If you win, don't get your nose high,
If you lose - don't cry
Man, don't you ever let other see your tears
December of 1941.
In order to capture
Southern Asia's resources by force,
Japan had deployed its Combined fleet
in the vast waters of Southern Pacific.
According to the Southern strategy, the unit,
tasked with protecting the operation's flanks and rear,
is the First Mobile Fleet -
a large unit of 30 ships,
with 6 aircraft carriers as the core.
Episode 1
Surprise attack on Pearl Harbor
On the fateful day, December 8th, at dawn,
the 1st Mobile Fleet carried out
a secret 5800km expedition,
infiltrating the waters
360km north of Pearl Harbor.
Chief, the task force is ready for sortie.
I have...
been in charge of getting us all up to here, but now...
The rest is up to you.
The latest Intel had arrived.
Enemy forces anchored at Pearl Harbor are as follows:
Battleship - 9, second-class cruiser - 3,
seaplane tender - 3, destroyer - 17.
Aircraft carriers and heavy cruisers are all dispatched.
No abnormal fleet preparations noticed.
The aircraft carrier is not there?
But it's Sunday,
so it will definitely be back until tomorrow.
Any chance you meet it on your way there?
If they meet it, they'll have the upper hand.
But they won't be able to attack Pearl Harbor.
What does it matter?
Sinking a carrier would be just as good.
It's time.
Got it! Sir, if you excuse me.
Counting on you!
If we're spotted by the enemy's carrier while
the attack party is away on the mission, we're screwed.
Second wave of attack vehicles
would still be here!
This would not be enough.
We'll still end up losing some ships.
What did I tell you before?
Cutting the Gordian Knot!
Precisely! Go there and do what you do best!
The first ones to take off
are carrier-based fighters of the Zero type.
Also known as Zero Fighters.
Equipped with two 20mm machine guns,
this is a maneuverability-focused aircraft.
Its true power becomes apparent in dog-fighting.
This is the main fighter of the Japanese Navy.
Victory by all means
I'm off!
Next goes Nakajima B5N.
Its job is to carry up to 800 kilograms of torpedoes.
It's capable of marching far behind enemy lines.
This aircraft's article of pride
is horizontal bombing accuracy rate of over 50%.
If only I were younger...
You'd fly, too?
Most certainly. In the avant-garde.
6:05, first wave of attack squadron #1 takes off,
and at 7:15 already, the second wave will be dispatched.
A total of 350 aircraft, 765 people in them
congregated into one huge formation in the sky
somewhere in the middle of the Pacific Ocean.
Right now, they are preparing
to change the course of history.
Among those, the Aichi D3A carrier-based bomber.
During a nose dive, it has an accuracy rate of 80%.
Pilots put infinite trust in this model.
It sure is cloudy up here.
Captain, by listening to Honolulu broadcast,
we'll always be up to speed.
They don't suspect a thing.
Playing some carefree jazz.
And now, a weather forecast.
Silence!
Over Oahu, the sky is partly cloudy.
The wind blows at about 7.5 km/h.
Hey, our dear enemies have even been so kind
as to tell us the forecast.
Cut it out! You're forgetting
there's still plenty of Japanese living on Hawaii.
Nothing useful for us on that radio.
Only distraction from the hell captain is taking us to.
We're at Oahu.
Sure is a beautiful thing.
Like heaven on earth.
Almost makes it a pity to bomb.
Alright, we're approaching it!
Assault formation!
The squadron commander just reported back.
"Tora, tora, tora," isn't it?
Admiral, the captain's plane
just transmitted the assault signal.
Admiral...
They've done it. They made it there!
First attack successful!
Alright, execute the battle plans
throughout the region!
Thus, the thunder of war
has been unleashed upon Pacific.
The enemy is still unaware?
Two carriers are nowhere to be seen.
Missing, after all? Whatever. We'll be sure to intercept them
on their way back during the second wave.
Engage!
Damn you!
Would you just look at this mess?
Our fleet is blown to smithereens!
I saw it. I saw it all.
I was still in my nightwear when it started.
Admirals, it is dangerous
if you two stay in the same place.
Our entire fleet is beheaded
if something happens to you!
Alright, I'll be in my office
on the opposite side of the building.
Still would you look at what the Japanese did!
I will locate our own aircraft carriers
and have them chase the enemy away.
Alright, the anti-aircraft has been suppressed.
Now it's naval bombers turn!
Alright, first wave had used all its ammo.
Second wave comes in about 30 minutes.
Take a good picture of the damage.
Okay.
A supposed Japanese parachute unit landing has been but a hoax.
Even so, I can't help but appreciate
the enemy's strategy.
A sweeping blow.
What's good about "sweeping blow?" This strategy
is only used when there's a material advantage.
But now that they've done this, there's no doubt our people
would spare no penny to avenge this treachery.
Admiral!
Is this a Japanese bullet?
Oh, why didn't it pierce my chest as well?
Alright, I've made sure of the results.
All our vehicles returned already. Turn back, too.
Jettison that pile of scrap!
Move it, you idiot!
Second wave cannot take off!
Jettison into the sea anything that clutters the deck!
Don't fret, the sea is warm around here!
Okay, emergency landing!
Attaway.
You returned safely!
Had us all worried here!
Reporting! Our attacking forces...
Yes, the results. What are results?
Yessir! According to my observations,
4 battleships are sunk, 4 more badly damaged.
So all of them?
All except for Enterprise and Lexington
that weren't present.
Aircraft carriers, then?
So the aircraft carriers survived?
We should strike back!
They'll be around for 2 or 3 days more!
Don't say nonsense!
We don't have any tankers in the vicinity.
Think it'll appear here at once,
just as we summon it with Morse?
Their carriers are out of fighting shape!
If we manage to get to any of them, even at the expense
of revealing ourselves, we've naught to fear!
So the carriers?
Admiral! Each carrier is ready
to commence the second wave of attack!
Should we even go for a second wave?
The enemy will definitely strike again.
Our anti-aircraft facilities are prepared now.
Is there any civilian unrest?
People are utterly disoriented.
The radio broadcast could not be continued.
What about enemy's carriers?
The enemy is supposedly stationed to the south,
in the direction of the Wake Island.
Dispatch the patrol aircraft again.
Admiral, should we deploy it to the north?
Coming from the south would make a lot more sense.
Listen, we have to find the Japanese carriers at any cost.
And then we blow it to pieces.
What about operational objectives?
All are met.
We expect that the American Pacific Fleet won't be able
to operate from Pearl Harbor for at least 6 more months.
Our mission of protecting the flanks and the rear
of Southern operation, has been accomplished.
We have orders to commence multiple attacks!
We also have the orders to be as cautious as possible,
making sure the losses are minimized.
What of the enemy's condition?
Reports say, the enemy's preparedness for the attack
has been significantly bolstered.
Our losses in the second wave of attack are 24 planes.
Next wave would suffer even more losses.
Besides, the enemy aircraft carrier...
Let's go for the night attack!
Just for that purpose, we have a specially trained
night-time torpedo bombing team!
Are you suggesting a gamble?
Better than returning
without playing the trump!
Aviation officers!
It's dangerous to delve too deep
into strategy planning.
Our goal is to find a balance between attacking
in favorable conditions and operating with limited forces.
Japan's industrial capabilities
are not meant for mass-producing warships.
But the grand-admiral of the Navy wants us
to sink as many enemy ships as possible in one go.
To the west, the weather is deteriorating.
They would be able to take off,
but landing would become increasingly difficult.
What can this mean?
As you can see, we've taken the course
to the north-northwest.
There won't be any more waves?
I told them not to call it off.
Damn it, this is driving me crazy.
They say admirals are prone to panic attacks.
Those guys see airplanes
as nothing more than axillary force.
All they care about are ships with big guns,
blissfully ignorant of the new era about to come.
Always so faint-hearted, damn it.
Length of service had gone to their heads.
If only it was up to Yamaguchi...
Prepare an airplane!
I'm going to Headquarters on Akagi.
Captain!
Forget it, I'll do it myself!
I'll talk to the Chief!
Let me go at once!
This is a mutiny! Let me go!
Japanese army making a landing at Barbers Point
turned out to be a false rumor.
All we hear is false rumors.
We're not as scared of actual Japanese army as of rumors.
Soldiers on land report
countless cases of friendly fire.
Enterprise sent 17 liaison aircraft,
all of which have been shot down.
Excuse me, radar station reports,
the enemy is to the north.
However, why is there no new wave of attack?
Our gasoline tank is still untouched.
Now that they've done it,
we're probably getting withdrawn to San Francisco.
Pearl Harbor waters are shallow.
The vessels would be easy to recover.
This debacle had once again
proved battleships obsolete.
This will convince even the hardline legislators, whether they like it or not, that the aircraft carriers are the future.
The old man will sure be overjoyed.
Old man?
President Roosevelt.
He is a proponent of carriers doctrine,
itching to start building them en masse.
After choosing such a strategy,
they don't bring it to completion...
Did their commanders lack the guts for it?
Or is it...
Or is it?
A trap?
Our submarine had located an enemy fleet
heading for Pearl Harbor.
Enterprise, too?
Must be. The likelihood of that is very high.
Just a likelihood?
We had to rely on a variety
of likelihoods to make it here!
Idiot! You strike the iron while it's still hot!
There is a time to scatter stones
and a time to gather them.
Admiral, I have a suggestion.
Operational objectives have been met.
We now lack Intel on the enemy.
And due to the bad weather coming our way,
our fuel supply is also jeopardized.
I think, it's best that we now return the whole fleet
back to Japan safely, while we still can.
The true battlefield for our Imperial Navy
lies in the southern waters.
Shouldn't we take on our enemy
in a decisive battle of fleets, fair and square?
That's right, the Indian Ocean awaits!
Course to north!
At that moment, there was no one in Akagi high command,
able to predict, with full confidence,
what would be the effect of further waves of attack.
Therefore, it remains an article of debate to this day,
whether or not the additional waves of attack
would have changed the course of Pacific War.
Some accuse them of lacking guts,
others are more discreet and don't throw words around.
However, it is said that a truly talented commander
would never lose sight of his objectives,
and is able to take a critical decision
without batting an eye.
Conversely, if you let the situation at hand
influence your decision at a moment like this,
no satisfactory result is to be expected
after losing sight of your objective.
The Pacific War taught us the preciousness of peace.
But also bequeathed to us numerous lessons on how to live.
June 1942.
Two major task forces -
Japanese and American
spot one another at a measly distance of just 240km,
in the Battle of Midway.
How do you approach the opponent's condition,
how do you assess it?
And how would you fight him?
The commanders employ
all of their reckoning and intuition.
Deeming conditions favorable,
America seizes the chance.
Just as it was about to dispatch its second attack unit,
Japan's mobile fleet
has been engulfed
in a swarm of American dive bombers.
Need just a little more time!
If American bomber attack comes at least 5 minutes late,
the Battle of Midway
will become another sore spot for them.
However, was this 5 minutes window
just a stroke of fate?
The Pacific War is told to have its own Battle of Sekigahara,
which is this one, Battle for Midway.
Please witness more of the fateful decisions
being taken next week.
Animentary: Decision
Episode 2
Battle of Midway (Part 1)
If you're a man, let's put your strength to test
If you are a man, keep your hopes burning
If you are a man, don't lose your heart
Because there's just you and me, a man and a man
Very same bright crimson blood flowing in us both
Brought to you by the Sorcery Party
ѫ~ѫ
"Lux in Tenebris"
Translation by Perevodildo
Quality Checking by Ziusudra
Supplementary materials by History Asian
RAW by Moozzi2