Ippei Yasuda inauguration party
Well, congratulations, Mr. Yasuda!
But like a true maverick, your offspring ended up getting employed at such a peculiar place!
It is, indeed, such a headache. This fellow has no idea what he got involved into.
The 53rd Minister Mr. Shibata is attending as well.
It's nothing compared to General Secretary Kawamura
or Yamazaki of the Fukuyama Domain.
But what a first class party it is!
You bet! No wonder since this is a party for the successor of Yasuda Inc, estimated first or second in Japan!
You finally arrived!
Yes, Grandfather Honda...
I was looking for you since a while ago.
But I still don't seem to find Ippei.
It's too pompous. He'd never attend such an inflated party on a mere occasion of his inauguration.
Too bad, too bad. The party of this scale is incomplete without him.
Now that the time has come for him to leave the nest.
By any chance, can this person be the Business Federation chairman Honda?
It's unbelievable how even his fiancee is among the invited guests!
Hitomi Misaki. There.
Her domain spans from Japan's political and business world to the world of yakuza.
No wonder for the Old Man of Northeast's granddaughter.
So she is the sole heir to all the political and financial power of this old man, huh?
My skies
Criminal chapter
Station calling Kyobashi vehicle 3-5.
Kyobashi 3-5 copy, over.
Investigate the young woman body in the river as soon as you can.
Roger that, will do right away.
On the way to the scene.
Kyobashi, do you copy?
Must be a suicide. No signs of a violent death. It does not look like a homicide.
You think so, huh? Still, it feels like something's off.
Probably was a pretty lass, though. Did you see the face?
Shame her time was so short.
A young and pretty lady, she doesn't seem to have reasons to commit suicide in the middle of night.
You can only speak for yourself. Life is a zebra. Even for the pretty ladies.
You were in the lounge.
The atmosphere was not to my taste.
I see no issue in Ippei becoming a police officer.
However, if you are to become a police officer... I want you to be a police officer only you can be.
Tonight's party served the same purpose.
I understand.
Do you mind if I use this hotel?
It's much more convenient than going to work from Yasuda residence.
I'm not sure at what time I will be leaving and returning home from now on.
I can no longer operate under the Yasuda umbrella.
Feel free to use it however you please. Forget that it belongs to me, it belongs to you now.
Thank you...
Detective Tamura, your tea!
You think now's the time for tea parties?! Take it away!
What are you waiting for?!
If you have nothing else to do, start swabbing the toilets!
Okay!
Well, well, Tamura. I can understand your frustration, but such is our line of work.
In spite of all our efforts, we have close it!
That kind of untimely demise is too miserable for such a beauty!
The deceased was a youthful lass.
Are we... Are we really going to bargain with such bastards?
How can we look our families in the eyes after that?!
How can we call this a suicide? The woman was clearly murdered!
But we have to give up without even trying?
Following the example of the pile of previous girls, the case has been issued a Stop command.
How come?
They say she was a girl of easy virtue. Ended up being kidnapped by a gang of kid bikers.
Then what?
Eventually, those kids ended her life, one way or another.
One of them turned out to be the younger son of Yotaro Atagawa, the Minister of Health.
Well, they just sealed it off with "suicide."
In exchange for director's promotion, it seems.
Hey, trainee! Where are you going?
To enforce the law upon Atagawa!
What?!
You do understand that will be the end of you?
If you stir up that case, you will be out of detectives before new year's eve!
I'm not joking.
To catch a scoundrel that is ought to be caught, one doesn't have to be a detective or anything of the kind.
You do not seem to have heard me well.
This case has to be closed.
What happened is nothing but a corny suicide.
Just a wretched girl, unwilling to take part in marriage of convenience.
Well, since you already came here, this is for the two of you — a compensation for the taxi ride.
Mr. Naito from the Ministry of Social Affairs.
Is that you, Mr. Naito? I have a remarkable story for you.
H-Hey, you!
The Minister of Health son... That's right. Yoichiro Atagawa.
- How dare you!
- The deal with him is...
For the time being, his courage is in a bit of decline.
Asshole, what are you trying to pull...
It's been a while, sorry to interrupt your vacation. Ippei talking.
There's one fellow that'd like to have a little talk. Will pass the phone now.
This is Atagawa!
What?!
S-Such a... Such a ridiculous thing...
Who was it you called back then?
Issei Wakabayashi.
Wakabayashi is...
Prime Minister, right?
Nothing special.
You turned out to be a resourceful one...
Boss, did you not have enough?
Don't say stupid! Today your successful detective career has started!
We have to celebrate it. Get filthy drunk! Have fun!
Turn right around this corner.
Here, here!
Yep, that's the place. Gramps! How is it going?
Well, if it is kingpin Tamura who is asking, then it's going swimmingly!
Gramps, don't blend our shochu tonight. We will only drink rock-hard branded one!
This fella's first success has to be commemorated.
Understood! Rock-hard one it is.
I-I'll go take a quick piss.
Not!
Leave me be!
I'm not trying to take anything away from you. See, baby?
Stop it, you backstreet cockroach.
Did you just mutter something to me?
Merely said you're a backstreet cockroach.
What?
You deaf?
Damn jackass, you're not getting away with it!
You're fucking noisy!
Are you a Marubo henchman?
Shut the fuck up!
Bloody prick... What did I ever do to you?
What happens next, depends on this mechanism's will.
You're too nervous for a chinpira.
A pistol? Hey! What kind of mobster skirmish is that? Quit it!
None of your business!
What is it, Ippei?
You picked the wrong people to fool around with!
Why, isn't it Tamura from Kyobashi Dept?
M-Mr. Komiya...
I guess that kid is also a minion for your office?
Yeah...
Yakuza and detectives have one thing in common - if you ever see one, get out the way.
Yakuza are also people! The way you treated him right now is totally unacceptable!
Hey, hey, are you trying to sermonize me? Kyobashi rookie training program sucks hard, it seems!
Tamura, I caught this man molesting a girl. Detain him to see if there are other sins to his name.
Who is that ruffian?
Boss of Marubo, Field Officer Komiya from the main office.
Their department deals with the organized crime. And no one does it better than this astounding man.
If Mr. Komiya bothered to kick his ass, there must be some reason. That man has to have his hands dirty.
Pardon my lateness. Good morning.
Yes, sorry we had to wake you early in the morning.
No, work comes first for me.
Because of some prejudices, the guy from Nakano remains completely tongue-tied round the clock.
I tried to approach him as well, but to no avail.
However, recently he yielded to crack if we call up that young handsome detective to handle him.
I am Yasuda.
What's the deal with you?
You are one of those geta-faced thickskulls! Get the fuck out!
Who do you think you are!?
I only agreed to spill it to the young one.
You've seen yourself how obstinately tight-lipped I can be while seeing some bulky face around!
You! What kind of big shot do you think you are to keep barking like that!?
The interrogations are supposed to be conducted by two!
Do it your way and you're getting nothing out of me.
You dare...
I-It's fine... I'll try to somehow do it by myself.
Bullshit!
Last night, the getaheads confronted me with my previous criminal record, neatly arranged.
There was but one skeleton in the cupboard they omitted.
What?
In Toyama, it makes three chicks this year.
But a way out that I could see in your eyes...
is your unspoiled spirit.
What I saw in those eyes...
was a sharp recollection of all the poor girls.
I will return to my hometown, start the life from the scratch once again.
A rape show?
The guy from Nakano decided to clean his conscience before stepping off the slippery slope.
A rape show in Ikebukuro, then?
Come to think of it, the number of college girls going missing in this area is abnormally high.
Hey! This is a case for the Field Officer Komiya from the main department!
The Kaisei Group is rapidly consolidating its power in the Johoku district.
There's no doubt that their prime funding source is this show.
The rape show is being held in the Matsuba Motel.
Overnight, it yields them about 300 000 000 yen or even more.
Finally, in regards to the rape show itself...
Some way or another, they kidnap college girls and even female office workers.
Not bound by any reservations, they proceed straight to the improvisation.
For this show, they use unsuspecting girls, each one not more than once.
Among spectators, there are even those who crave to perform a rape upon a defenseless girl.
The suburbs of Tokyo harbor way too many cases of female students suddenly going missing.
They are probably being used not only for the duration of the rape show but afterwards as well.
Finally, the next show will be held next Sunday, on 24th!
I-Impressive, isn't it? Such operation with just 20 people!
Nothing special. Mr. Komiya always means business.
This operation is supposed to be a joint enterprise of the Main office, Kyobashi and of course, Ikebukuro departments.
That's about all I got to comment on everyone's mission.
Now, chief of staff Komiya will provide you with a terse briefing.
The opponent is the yakuza of Kaisei Group.
As you are well aware, their back appears to be at all times covered by a huge political party of their own.
It appears as well that this party controls us, the police.
But we will remain steadfast, because we're the best, aren't we!?
Sending innocent girls straight to hell one after another with nothing but the sheer intention of making money is unforgivable!
Is that right, people?
Whatever the motive is, such actions cannot be forgiven. It befalls on us to make them feel the consequences!
Because we are the detectives.
That is the world you happened to be living in!
There are people rejecting basic humanity, acting solely in their selfish interests!
There is no place for tears or hot-blooded considerations when dealing with criminal organizations! Did I make myself clear?!
Os!
Yeah, good job. Is Matsuba here?
Yes. He is waiting inside.
Kaisei Enterprise
Bow!
Os!
Well done!
Glad to be working with you!
Please make yourself at home, bro.
Are you done sorting out the woman?
This time it's going swimmingly. We nailed a superb belle.
The show is supposed to be held tomorrow, on 24th...
But...?
It's Komiya from Marubo. He has been acting funny lately.
He may have got a leak about what we're up to.
He is scheming all year around, and you can't be constantly anxious about it.
Besides, the cops have already busted one of our guys, and there's no chance he spills the beans.
First, think of our Kansai customers that have already hit the road and are on their way.
There's no way to cancel it now.
At any rate, there's also my father with General Secretary Kawamura and Atagawa's second son, who we can show around.
You never know what they can do to return the favor.
I-Is that really so?
Well, that means we can proceed without worrying!
Either way, please let me handle this.
I guess so. Well, I entrust this to you.
Tonight we act according to plan. The bastards are holding the rape show.
Now, listen closely! We can't know for sure what is going on inside.
The show begins at 23:00. It's 11 at night.
Our deadline for storming the building is 11:45.
The department chief will instruct you on the scene layout.
I will need you to storm the crime scene simultaneously and without a delay.
Hence, Field Officer Komiya will be in the vanguard, breaking the way through for you.
Tamura from Kyobashi.
Os!
As well as Mr. Honbe.
Here.
Kitagawa and Ishikawa from the Kyobashi Dept will go as well.
- OK!
- Roger.
Takei and Murata from the Main Office will also join us.
- Roger!
I will also require Sugiyama and Sakurai from Ikebukuro.
Finally, it is myself. There would be 9 of us — disguised and waiting patiently for the signal.
As soon as we rush into the building, our standby agents will get into the position and block the rear exit.
The three remaining squads will secure the east completely.
Everyone take a good look at this Matsuba motel sketch. Have it nailed firmly in your head!
Alright, the briefing is over. Operation starts!
E-Excuse me, am I staying on the lookout again?
Do you believe such is fair to do? I was the first one to ever stumble upon this case!
You're a bit short on guts for that, Ippei. Someone has to stay on the lookout.
You think it's fair? Such assignment is fair?
Yasuda, let's take a walk.
Uh-huh... Okay!
Name is Mayumi Okawa.
Yasuda, this is your tonight's companion.
Now, listen closely. I need you two to become a pair of lovebirds so as to infiltrate the Matsuba.
As you have already grasped, we — the shock troops — will enter the building on your cue.
If someone gives the game away, the edge of shock troops perfect timing is scrapped.
We'll only catch small fish.
When to pull the trigger is up to you two. Everything depends on you. That's what I'm saying.
Understood?
- Yes.
You'd make a convincing Latin Lover.
Yes.
There is still some time. Get along well and join us in the conference room.
L-Lovebirds then...
I-I guess I should better let you change.
Perhaps.
Alright, but aside from your company and a fancy tuxedo, Ms. Okawa...
What is on your mind at such a time?!
It can only be on my mind at such a time.
If we don't make convincing enough lovebirds, we're busted.
From now on, I will be loving you with all sincerity.
Please be so kind to love me reciprocally.
Hotel Matsuba
Matsuba Motel is comprised by four aboveground floors and one underground.
The show is being held in the underground hall.
Kaisei group has one lookout at the front entrance.
Two at the rear door.
Three more patrol the driveway to the motel from the Meiji-dori Avenue intersection.
Yeah, the wiring is completely bare!
I thought so! How does it look, can you fix it?
Yeah, I'll think of something.
Hey, hey, now's not the time to do the electrics maintenance.
Something like a power outage would be fatal.
Not to worry. Your side of the road is not connected to this pole.
Hey, you need insulation fiber?
Yeah, that'd come in handy.
Hurry up, okay?
East of the motel is the main boulevard. Roadworks. Four men, including Mr. Honbe.
Mr. Honbe, won't that look suspicious if you don't move one bit?
It would take one an excessive mental effort to suspect someone with a face and appearance like mine.
Well, if anything, such a face and appearance do not fit a general laborer as well.
You wouldn't want to pick a fight with an oldster, that's for certain.
500 meters away from the motel, 13 more plainclothed detectives await orders in the microbus.
Additionally, 200 meters to the west, 30 more agents waiting for orders in a marked truck.
Chef! Another guest has arrived!
With this one, it gives us a total of 38 guests. They just sealed the backdoor shutter.
I see. This one was probably the last guest they are expecting.
Time?
11:05.
Boss, I've seen it just now
Chairman and His Grace are here.
What time is it?
We've already waited until 11:10.
Alright!
Make sure everyone is on the edge of their seats about meeting a young lady!
Is there a single chance... A single chance?
What time is it?
11:18.
Have those animals already started?
This way please.
Now I wait... here?
That's a fine lass.
Whatever it takes to please Your Grace.
We made sure to secure an exclusive belle for today's occasion.
Hey Hey...
It's still too early.
If we rush in before the show is on its peak, the whole game is down the drain.
Ms. Okawa, let me see your watch.
Too soon. Let's bide some more time.
Ms. Okawa, when did you graduate?
I'm a part of the 45th generation, so it's last year's October.
Turns out you are a mentor to me?
I guess...
Look out, the guard is coming.
Ms. Okawa, you are astonishingly beautiful in your plain clothes.
I love you...
Brilliantly improvised. The guard totally bought it.
What?! What kind of place is this?
No... No!
No!!
11:30. 15 minutes until the storm deadline. Let's go in.
They probably ordered the motel front desk to turn everyone away with 'no vacancies.'
In that case, I will knock out the lookout to let you rush in all at once.
Then, the fire alarm will go off. Start the storm on that signal.
Please... Let me go!
He penetrated her!
Ah, I'm so sorry. We are totally out of vacancies today.
Is that so? Not gonna work?
The other hotel was also full to the brim.
Maybe if we wait here a bit...
You see, like I said before...
Now that is just straight up rude, bro. Why don't you carry on outside, like you did before?
I am sorry...
If you say so...
Help me!
Ms. Okawa! Hit the bell!
Okay!
Let's move!
At last! Get em!
Hey, the police is here!
Keep going going going going!
Outta my way!
They don't want us in! Let's punch our way through!
They really are hiding something!
You have some guts, aren't you?
Out of the way!
The rear door is secured! Squad three and squad four join the assault!
Don't fret! We can't let them in!
Everyone freeze! Not a single bastard moves!
You're all under arrest!
Then, we'll have our leave.
Stay where you are, you, on the balcony!
And everyone who is with you!
Guests who just watched are arrested too!
Quit pretending you didn't hear my order to stay still!
Amateur.
- Hey!
- Don't, Ippei!
Mr. Komiya!
Mr. Komiya...
Unforgivable...
Widespread gang enforcement investigations!!
11 Kaisei Group members arrested
What's wrong with those newspapers? Not a word about the brutal rape show!
Yes. First Investigation Dept.
It is me.
Okay. Roger that.
Ippei, where are you off to?
To meet Mr. Komiya.
Mr. Yasuda came to see you.
Let him in.
Glad to see you came, young man!
Those gentlemen are fourth investigation dept superintendent Keishi Kameda,
Hidehisa Orei of the main office senior executives,
and finally, the one sitting in the middle, is the renowned Congressman Mr. Ishioka.
Each one had his reputation publicly tarnished at least once.
Moreover, this applies to me as well.
These guys' word is the law to you.
Thanks for giving us a positive answer anyway.
Wait just a moment more.
Mr. Komiya, what is the meaning of this?
I saw the newspapers...
There was nothing whatsoever concerning the brutal rape show.
Mr. Komiya, you don't say...
That's just the way life is.
Even the 22-agent investigation cannot alter the flow of life.
Are you being pressured from above? They issue a Stop command to our investigation!?
Is this still a thing even to these days!?
These guys put their own interests on the prime spot, above any laws and regulations.
Such a thing... Why the hell were we even doing all of this?
I think you've had enough, Komiya.
I told you to wait...
I will cease the investigation like you told me to.
But here, in private, I can personally give you just one possible answer.
So meet my answer!
Komiya! What are you doing!?
Are you out of your mind!?
Nothing wrong with me!
To your son of a bitch Congressman playing pet for his Grand Secretary,
and to tame underling "detectives" from the Fourth Investigation Department,
this is the Komiya's answer!
Mr. Komiya was...
reassigned to a small island in the boondocks.
So he is a true castaway now...
At this point, tendering a resignation to turn a new leaf seems more favorable.
It is not so. Despite all of that, Mr. Komiya is still a police officer. A real one.
He is a real detective. He showed it to me. And he showed it to that man...
What is the police then? What is public security?
Therefore, I made up my mind about what I will do.
If a scoundrel has to be caught, I go and catch him.
If even the police itself is paid to become a hindrance to catching him, then I don't need it at all!
If catching a criminal requires money, any amount is worth it!
We have to catch that scoundrel, because he absolutely has to be caught!
I cannot answer now. I told you not to call me for longer than five beeps.
But I thought it's different for calls from Mr. Yasuda.
Then connect at once!
Hey, doing fine?
Y-Yes... It's been a long time.
Are you busy tonight?
What's the matter? Why did you fall silent?
There is not a single thing more important to me now than all the newfound matters you have to tend to.
We're closing the case tomorrow.
Would you like to dine with me tonight? A have a reserve at Princess of Hakone.
Yes...
You have become a real police officer, Ippei.
What you said back then, do you still feel that way about me?
Are you still okay with me becoming a cop?
After becoming a cop, one suddenly stars being a target for all sorts of people.
All I want is just to follow you wherever.
Kyobashi Police Department
So hot...
Indeed, there are places way better than the office to spend midsummer in.
That's it!
Born in March of 1943. Permanent residence in Okayama Prefecture.
Personal file A14. Two cases of murder, five of blackmail.
Participation in organized crime: young successor of Kaisei Group.
Whose file do you have here?
Yoichi Toyoda's.
You mean Toyoda from the Kaisei Group?
Yes.
Toyoda's record is not limited with a rape show organization.
This may allow us to corner Kaisei Group to liquidation.
Not happening. That son of a bitch Toyoda is too bright a smartass to let that happen.
There's a reason he has not once revealed his true colors in all those years.
That is not entirely so. With this, we should be able to take him down.
What?
Two years ago, Toyoda had a woman, Yasuko Ogura. Ultimately, she went missing.
Immediately after that, he married his current wife.
So what of that?
It is obviously Toyoda's work! I'll go out for a moment.
You know where this is going, don't you, Mr. Honbe?
He is following Mr. Komiya's footsteps.
Nothing will come out of this. She just went missing with no loose ends.
Yes. If you say so. I will get to it right away. Ippei's request?
Yes...
I heard you.
I'm going out. Bring a car to the front door at once.
Hurry up please.
Excuse me, can I ask you a small favor? Which way is Shiro Sakaguchi's house?
Y-You want to hire me as a scout?
I'm told you have a knack of obtaining miscellaneous intelligence.
And that you make your living by getting the said intelligence.
Yes...
My special offer is a rate of 20 000 000 yen per year.
Additional 300 000 for each important piece of intelligence obtained.
Finally, I will fully cover any expenses you incur while gathering the intelligence.
If you also hire a number of intel gathering assistants, that would be dandy.
What do you say?
Why are you even asking... what I say?
Guchi, you weasel!
That's way too much money!
Just as I thought, this lake is a dead end.
Visibility in the water is less than 2 meters.
Algae growth is also present. No diver can operate in such conditions.
But you say that bastard Toyoda doused a woman in concrete and drowned her here?
I wonder if it's just a hearsay.
I know I'm screwed if I bring you a dummy.
It's a lead from Ashiya.
It's not the kind of intel one shares with police. This one is animate.
Pardon my candor, but the police is nowhere near as well aware as I am.
You distrust the most trustworthy one.
You will be treated the same way yourself.
Too bad, even if this is indeed the truth, you can see for yourself:
our chances of raising the cadaver from this water are 100% of failure.
The testimony worth nothing if he'll just dismiss it with an alibi.
The body is essential. We're not getting anywhere without it!
Ippei, do you finally give up?
It's but a first step towards crushing the Kaisei group.
Toyoda is the cornerstone of that citadel.
He has to be caught by any means.
There's no going forward until Toyoda is caught, whatsoever.
Hitomi, please purchase about a square mile from here to that mountain on the other side.
Okay.
I will dam the valley, so we could bulldoze it.
Using the pumps, I will drain this lake dry.
What?
Hitomi, start the construction works tomorrow.
Ippei Yasuda of Yasuda Conglomerate Confirms Acquisition of Lake Masumi
Construction started at an incredible pace
A giant leisure center is being built by Yasuda Conglomerate?!
Lake Masumi waters are emptied into the Shimozawa Valley
Just a few more days left...
Yes. Should be done by tomorrow evening.
Yes. This is Ippei. Right. The day after tomorrow it will be completed.
Please arrange an arrest warrant. Yes. Count on you.
It was established that the entire construction process was initiated on Mr. Yasuda's personal whim of finding a cadaver in the water
W-What?!
The bottom of the lake revealed a concrete encased body!!
Tenacious investigation pays off!
Kaisei Group young successor Yoichi Toyoda arrested!!
Suspected of murder
Mistress killer
She followed him to death!!
Kaisei Group young successor Yoichi Toyoda arrested on charges of murder!!
Body remains found in the Masumi Lake!!
You are a complete fucking moron!
Come on, come on. Don't make a lady wait. You can go now, go!
Are you content with the ultimate conclusion of this case?
Yes. Thanks to your participation.
Now that we have its most vital part firmly under control, nothing stays in the way of smashing the Kaisei Group.
Without a name or a country,
Namae mo kuni mo nai
Umaretate no genki
The new vigor is being born
All right donna hane wo kureru no
All right, what kind of feathers can you bestow upon me?
Bokura wa itsu datte
As fate would have it, we are destined
Kaze wo hiita mama sa
To forever be exposed to cold
Oiru no kireta ashita no puroguramu daiji ni mawashiteru
When I run out of oil, I will carefully turn the page
For the program of tomorrow
Oikakete oikaketemo tsukamenai mono bakari sa
Of all the things I chased, of all the things I'm chasing
Not a single one is withing my grasp
I loved you, I keep loving you
But the closer I get, the less I can see
Aishite aishitemo chikazuku hodo mienai
Taiyo to hokori no
Both the sun and the smell of dust
Nioi wo oboeteru
Are fresh in my memory up to this day
All right donna tane wo maita no
All right, whichever kind of seeds I sow here
Boku ga kimi ni tsuita
I will keep on walking after you
Even though with all the lies I told that day,
Ano hi no uso yori mo
We will only go further and further away,
Without ever showing a tear
Jouzu ni jouzu ni hagurete yuku
Namida mo sasowazu ni
Of all the things I chased, of all the things I'm chasing
Not a single one is withing my grasp
Oikakete oikaketemo tsukamenai Mono bakari sa
I loved you, I keep loving you
Aishite aishitemo
But the closer I get, the less I can see you
Chikazuku hodo mienai